<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<GameData>
  <LocalizedText>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Barricada|Barricadas</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1|2</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Barricada Reforçada|Barricadas Reforçadas</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1|2</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Armadilha|Armadilhas</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1|2</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Armadilha Modernizada|Armadilhas Modernizadas</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1|2</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_RELIGIOUS_NAME" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Conversão de Mortos-vivos</Text>
      <Gender>neutral</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_SCIENCE_NAME" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Sinal Sombrio|Sinais Sombrios</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1|2</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_CONTENT_TITLE" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Defesa Contra os Zumbis</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_WELCOME_TITLE" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Boas-vindas</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_WELCOME_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>O modo Defesa Contra os Zumbis traz uma ameaça perigosa à sua civilização: os mortos não se aquietam. Os zumbis podem se erguer das ruínas da guerra e, por atacarem suas terras e as dos outros, propagam a maldição letal. Tente impedi-los de subjugar suas cidades, pelo menos por mais um turno!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_TITLE" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Zumbis</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Zumbis são unidades corpo a corpo que vagam pelos ermos. Eles não podem pilhar suas melhorias; não é do interesse deles. Mas eles atacam imediatamente qualquer unidade que estiver perambulando em locais afastados. Portanto, abra o olho ao sair das suas cidades. Eles também podem atacar suas cidades, transformando a população destruída em mais zumbis...</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_2" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Quando uma unidade morre no mapa, ela tem uma pequena chance de retornar como unidade zumbi poucos turnos depois. Contudo, se uma unidade for destruída por um zumbi, ela certamente se reerguerá no turno seguinte. Porém, a ameaça dos mortos-vivos vai crescendo sempre: para cada zumbi eliminado no mundo, os zumbis restantes e os novos vão ficando cada vez mais fortes. Trate de saber o que está fazendo ao entrar em guerra com os mortos!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_3" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Locais Sagrados e Campi são uma solução temporária para a Horda de Zumbis. Usar o projeto Converter Mortos-vivos em um Local Sagrado, ou o projeto Sinal Sombrio em um Campus, permite que você assuma o controle dos zumbis por um breve período dentro dos limites da sua cidade, podendo virar a horda contra seus inimigos. Mas não se esqueça de estar a uma distância segura quando seu controle acabar... ou quando você interromper o controle estrategicamente. Além disso, seus espiões podem propagar a maldição letal aos seus inimigos com a ação Surto de Zumbis.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_TITLE" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Defesa</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Suas terras não estão indefesas contra a horda. Além dos projetos em Locais Sagrados ou Campi, seus construtores podem criar Barricadas ou Armadilhas para se defender de seus inimigos (vivos ou mortos). A Barricada causa uma pequena quantidade de dano a qualquer unidade hostil que passa por ela ou por painéis adjacentes, e a Armadilha causa uma grande quantidade de dano a qualquer unidade hostil que passa diretamente por ela. Eras posteriores podem conceder a habilidade de criar Barricadas ou Armadilhas mais poderosas.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_PARA_2" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Elas podem ser defesas poderosas contra os mortos-vivos, mas também podem ser úteis contra seus inimigos mais... vivazes... pois causam dano a qualquer tipo de inimigo. Planeje-as estrategicamente e você talvez sobreviva.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>O caráter sinistro dos zumbis está na ambiguidade. São simplesmente coisas que se mexem, ou são algum tipo de ser vivo? Defesas contra pessoas utilizam muitas coisas que simplesmente não se aplicam às carcaças ambulantes: dor, intimidação, cansaço. Arame farpado não é nada para quem não sente dor. Além disso, o armamento dos zumbis é limitado: eles não constroem trabucos nem disparam flechas. Portanto, as defesas contra os mortos tratam eles não como um inimigo pensante, mas como matéria em movimento: estacas afiadas que não buscam matar, mas imobilizar; torres com escadas retráteis, que fornecem refúgio contra inimigos estúpidos demais para escalar uma corda; valas que refreiam inimigos incapazes de construir pontes. Pelo menos, até que eles estejam em número grande demais.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Os mortos-vivos não se cansam. Essa é a grande vantagem deles: como um mar, eles estão sempre tentando derrubar as defesas erguidas para detê-los. As muralhas de madeira e bambu acabam se despedaçando, e até mesmo as muralhas de pedra desabam. É aqui que entram os materiais modernos: concreto armado e aço. Assim como a fortificação em estrela renascentista, com muralhas em ângulo, era projetada para desviar o impacto dos disparos de canhão, e não os absorver, o foco das defesas modernas é desviar os mortos- vivos, e não os deter. Com o implacável empurra-empurra dos mortos-vivos, os materiais flexíveis se dobram, mas não quebram. Superfícies lisas não dão apoio para os dedos ossudos, e comportas permitem a limpeza das valas e fossos com água, prevenindo a formação de pilhas de corpos, que podem superar formas mais antigas de defesa contra zumbis. Elas provavelmente nos protegerão. Provavelmente.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Embora as muralhas sejam um tipo de defesa que busca manter os inimigos do lado de fora, as armadilhas buscam eliminá-los, desacelerá-los ou imobilizá-los. E, embora os mortos-vivos sejam incansáveis, eles não são inteligentes. Basta um humano numa torre, com seu cérebro humano suculento, para servir de isca para os mortos (ou humanos hostis querendo eliminar um inimigo "desprotegido"), atraindo-os para perto, onde podem ser enfrentados. Porém, é bem mais complexo eliminar os mortos do que os inimigos humanos. Eles não podem ser afugentados nem feridos gravemente: é preciso destruí-los. As armadilhas antigas podiam usar piche em chamas, buracos camuflados ou simplesmente torres cheias de arqueiros. Isto é, até acabarem as flechas...</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Com o passar dos anos, aprendemos mais sobre a ameaça dos mortos-vivos. As primeiras armadilhas envolviam usar humanos vivos (voluntários ou não) como isca, mas os engenheiros desenvolveram substâncias ou animais substitutos. Além disso, balas de ponta oca ou antipessoal causam maior dano a tecidos e permitem mais precisão. Nem todo arqueiro é Guilherme Tell, capaz de acertar uma maçã com um tiro de besta. Fuzis e miras ajudam a "matar" com precisão, e abrigos com atiradores de precisão funcionam contra os mortos tão bem quanto contra outros inimigos. Petróleo refinado e napalm permitem desintegrar zumbis (ou inimigos humanos) de formas que não eram permitidas pelos materiais mais antigos. Além disso, as armadilhas modernas usam as fraquezas dos zumbis: fazer a horda de mortos-vivos marchar infinitamente em círculos, perseguindo um cérebro num trilho mecânico (como na corrida de cachorros), pode funcionar bem melhor do que um simples buraco.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Os zumbis se tornaram uma das figuras mais famosas das obras de terror. Mas a imagem de cadáveres vorazes e trôpegos, e principalmente a ideia de uma epidemia global de mortos-vivos, só surgiu em tempos recentes. Em muitas tradições folclóricas do Caribe, o zumbi, ou jumbie, é uma categoria geral de espírito malévolo, que deriva, por sua vez, de tradições da África Ocidental. Mas, no Haiti, o zumbi foi ressignificado, simbolizando todos os horrores da escravidão. Para os africanos escravizados da colônia francesa de São Domingos, a vida era quase insuportável. A morte, pelo menos, era uma promessa de alforria e, segundo a tradição, de retorno a um paraíso na África, onde finalmente poderiam ser livres. Mas o suicídio fecharia essa porta e faria o espírito desventurado permanecer para sempre no Caribe, eternamente escravizado: um zumbi.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Após a Revolução Haitiana, o zumbi surgiu no folclore local como servo de um feiticeiro maligno, ou, em algumas versões, como sacerdote de vodum (vudu). O zumbi, em transe ou reanimado, continuava a trabalhar para seu senhor, evocando um horrendo retorno à escravidão para um povo que havia lutado bravamente para conquistar e manter a liberdade. E foi nesse primeiro sentido que o zumbi surgiu na cultura popular global. Os filmes americanos usaram o zumbi como símbolo de magia exótica, muitas vezes em representações racistas de religiões caribenhas ou simplesmente "diferentes". Em outros locais, os zumbis surgiram como símbolo do medo de perder o emprego, seja pelo retorno da escravidão ou como metáfora da manifestação confusa e exploradora das novas formas de capitalismo em locais como a África do Sul.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Mas a maioria das pessoas deve estar familiarizada com as hordas popularizadas por George Romero em seu filme "A Noite dos Mortos-Vivos". Nele, Romero apresenta um mundo virado de ponta-cabeça, com os mortos insepultos voltando à vida. Particularmente, Romero nunca usa o termo "zumbi", chamando-os de "ghouls", em referência a um espírito canibal árabe. No fim do século XX, os zumbis tornaram-se uma nova metáfora, aparecendo como manifestações do consumismo acéfalo e desumano, receios da radiação nuclear ou a ameaça de revoltas sociais generalizadas. No século XXI, os zumbis foram associados ao medo de doenças e de colapso social. O enfoque do terror não era mais o medo de perder o controle sobre si, mas a fantasia de sobreviver após a aparente morte de todos. Aqui, os zumbis são uma força absolutamente destruidora, e você pode usar essa destruição a seu favor.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Melhoria inicial que não pode ser trabalhada, causa dano leve a unidades hostis que passarem por ela ou por painéis adjacentes a ela, e exerce zona de controle sobre essas unidades. Desbloqueada com Engenharia Militar e construída usando uma carga de Construtor. Não impede movimento de unidades por esse espaço.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Melhoria posterior que não pode ser trabalhada, causa dano moderado a unidades hostis que passarem por ela ou por painéis adjacentes a ela, e exerce zona de controle sobre essas unidades. Desbloqueada com Estriamento e construída usando uma carga de Engenheiro Militar. Não impede movimento de unidades por esse espaço.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Melhoria inicial que não pode ser trabalhada, causa dano moderado a unidades hostis que passarem diretamente por ela e esgota o movimento dessas unidades. Desbloqueada com Construção e construída usando uma carga de Construtor. Não impede movimento de unidades por esse espaço.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Melhoria posterior que não pode ser trabalhada, causa dano significante a unidades hostis que passarem diretamente por ela e esgota o movimento dessas unidades. Desbloqueada com Balística e construída usando uma carga de Engenheiro Militar. Não impede movimento de unidades por esse espaço.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_RELIGIOUS_DESCRIPTION" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Quando concluído, ganhe o controle dos zumbis atualmente no território desta cidade.  O controle dura 15 turnos.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_SCIENCE_DESCRIPTION" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Quando concluído, ganhe o controle dos zumbis atualmente no território desta cidade.  O controle dura 30 turnos.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_DESCRIPTION" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Unidade corpo a corpo hostil que tem chance de aparecer no mapa no local onde morreu uma unidade. A força a curta distância dela aumenta a cada zumbi eliminado no mundo todo. Se um zumbi destruir outra unidade, surgirá uma nova unidade zumbi no mesmo painel no turno seguinte. Se um zumbi reduzir a população de uma cidade, surgirá imediatamente uma nova unidade zumbi perto da cidade. Os zumbis atacam a unidade, cidade ou distrito defensável que estiver mais perto.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITCOMMAND_RELEASE_LEVY_DESCRIPTION" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Renuncie ao controle dessa unidade.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITCOMMAND_SPY_SUMMON_ZOMBIES_NAME" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Surto de Zumbis</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITCOMMAND_SPY_SUMMON_ZOMBIES_DESCRIPTION" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Quando concluído, tem chance de gerar um zumbi para cada painel trabalhado por esta cidade.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_MESSAGE" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Sucesso ao causar Surto de Zumbis</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_ENEMY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_MESSAGE" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Inimigo causou Surto de Zumbis</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Causa dano menor a unidades hostis que andarem sobre este painel e esgota o movimento dessas unidades.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_TRAP" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Causa dano moderado a unidades hostis que andarem sobre este painel e esgota o movimento dessas unidades.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_BARRICADE" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Causa dano menor a unidades hostis que andarem sobre este painel e sobre os que o cercam, e exerce zona de controle sobre essas unidades.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TOWERDEFENSE_ZOMBIE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_DESC" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>+{Property} Força de Mutação</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_SUMMARY" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Seu agente, {1_unitName}, obteve êxito ao  infectar a população {2_cityName: gender m?do; f?de; other?de;} {2_CityName}, criando uma Horda de Zumbis para atacar a cidade.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_ENEMY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_SUMMARY" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Um Espião inimigo foi bem-sucedido ao infectar sua população na cidade {1_cityName: gender m?do; f?de; other?de;} {1_CityName}, criando uma Horda de Zumbis que agora ameaça a sua cidade.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ALCAZAR_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ALCAZAR_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MAORI_PA_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MAORI_PA_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ROMAN_FORT_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ROMAN_FORT_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_FORT_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_FORT_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_VAMPIRE_CASTLE_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_VAMPIRE_CASTLE_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_GREAT_WALL_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_GREAT_WALL_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_BARRICADE}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_NAME" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Zumbi|Zumbis</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1|2</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Barricade|Barricades</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1|2</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Barricade renforcée|Barricade renforcées</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1|2</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Piège|Pièges</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1|2</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Piège modernisé|Pièges modernisés</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1|2</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_RELIGIOUS_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Transformation en zombies</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_SCIENCE_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Signal obscur</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_CONTENT_TITLE" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Défense zombie</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_WELCOME_TITLE" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Bienvenue</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_WELCOME_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Le mode Défense zombie introduit un nouveau type de menace pour votre civilisation : désormais, les morts ne reposent plus en paix. Les zombies peuvent émerger des cendres de la guerre, et tandis qu'ils ravagent vos territoires et ceux de vos voisins, la calamité se propage sans cesse. Tentez de les empêcher de submerger vos villes, au moins pendant encore un tour !</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_TITLE" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Zombies</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Les zombies sont des unités de combat rapproché errantes. Ils ne peuvent pas piller vos aménagements ; ça ne les intéresse pas vraiment. En revanche, ils s'en prendront immédiatement à toute unité traversant le territoire, alors prenez garde en déplaçant vos unités hors des villes. Ils peuvent aussi attaquer vos villes et transformer les populations décimées en nouvelles vagues de zombies…</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_2" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Lorsqu'une unité meurt sur la carte, il y a une petite chance pour qu'elle se transforme en unité zombie quelques tours plus tard. Cependant, si une unité est détruite par des zombies, la transformation sera automatique au tour suivant. La menace des morts-vivants croît lentement mais sûrement : pour chaque zombie tué dans le monde, les morts-vivants restants et les nouveaux zombies ne cessent de gagner en puissance. Pesez bien le pour et le contre avant de prendre les armes contre les morts !</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_3" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Les lieux saints et les campus fournissent une solution temporaire contre la horde zombie. Utilisez le projet Transformation des morts-vivants au lieu saint, ou Signal obscur au campus afin de prendre brièvement le contrôle des zombies à l'intérieur du territoire de votre ville, et ainsi les retourner contre vos ennemis. Mais faites attention à ce que vos unités soient hors de portée de la horde lorsque vous ne pourrez plus la contrôler, ou bien que vous choisirez stratégiquement de la libérer. Vos espions peuvent aussi propager la calamité zombie chez vos ennemis grâce à l'action Invasion zombie.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_TITLE" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Défense</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Vos terres sont sans défense face à la horde. En plus des projets dans les lieux saints ou les campus, vos bâtisseurs peuvent créer des barricades ou des pièges pour vous aider à repousser vos ennemis (morts ou vivants). Les barricades infligent des dégâts mineurs à toute unité hostile traversant la case ou les cases adjacentes. Les pièges infligent des dégâts importants à toute unité ennemie traversant la case. Au cours des ères plus tardives, vous pourrez créer des barricades et des pièges plus puissants.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_PARA_2" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Ces défenses sont efficaces contre les morts-vivants, mais aussi contre des cibles plus vivaces, car elles infligent des dégâts à n'importe quel type d'ennemi. Positionnez-les stratégiquement, et vous pourriez bien passer la nuit.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>L'étrangeté des zombies provient de leur nature ambiguë. Sont-ils de la simple matière animée, ou doit-on les considérer comme des êtres vivants ? Lorsqu'on se bat contre des adversaires humains, on utilise des armes qui ne fonctionnent pas sur les zombies : la douleur, l'intimidation ou l'épuisement. Des fils barbelés ne représentent pas un obstacle pour un être qui ne ressent rien. De plus, l'armement zombie est limité : ils ne construisent pas de trébuchet et ne tirent pas de flèches. Les défenses contre les zombies sont donc conçues non pas pour un adversaire doué de raison, mais pour un ennemi constitué de matière mouvante : les pieux affûtés ne cherchent pas à tuer, mais à immobiliser, les tours dotées d'échelles rétractables fournissent un refuge contre des ennemis dépourvus de cerveau leur permettant d'utiliser des cordes, et les fosses retiennent des adversaires incapables de construire un pont. Du moins, jusqu'à ce qu'ils soient trop nombreux.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Les morts-vivants ne se fatiguent jamais. C'est leur plus grand atout : comme l'océan, ils érodent constamment les défenses dressées contre eux. Les remparts de bambou finissent par se briser, et même les murs de pierre s'écroulent. C'est ici qu'interviennent les matériaux de l'ère moderne comme le béton armé ou l'acier. De la même manière que la forteresse en étoile de la Renaissance a été conçue pour dévier et non absorber l'impact des boulets de canon, les défenses modernes cherchent à mettre les zombies en échec plutôt que de simplement les arrêter. Les matériaux flexibles plient, mais ne cassent pas quand les morts s'y pressent sans relâche. Les surfaces lisses n'offrent aucune prise à leurs doigts osseux, les écluses permettent de vider les fosses et les douves afin d'empêcher un empilement de cadavres qui pourrait aider les zombies à franchir des défenses plus anciennes. Nous devrions être en sécurité à l'intérieur. En théorie.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Alors que les remparts constituent un type de défense conçu pour repousser les ennemis, les pièges sont pensés pour éliminer, ralentir ou immobiliser. Et les morts-vivants ont beau ne jamais se fatiguer, ils sont dépourvus d'intelligence. Un seul humain dans une tour, muni de son délicieux cerveau humain, peut constituer un appât suffisant pour attirer les morts à portée de tir (ou d'autres humains hostiles pensant avoir affaire à une cible facile). Cependant, il n'est pas aussi aisé de se débarrasser des morts que des vivants. On ne peut pas faire fuir les zombies, ni les blesser ; on peut uniquement les détruire. Les anciens pièges utilisés contre les zombies incluaient de la poix incandescente, des fosses dissimulées, ou simplement des tours remplies d'archers. Une défense efficace, du moins jusqu'à ce que la dernière flèche soit tirée...</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Avec les années, nous en avons appris davantage sur la menace zombie. Les pièges de jadis impliquaient l'utilisation de vies humaines (volontaires ou non) comme appâts, mais les ingénieurs ont développé des substituts animaux ou chimiques. De plus, les balles antipersonnelles ou les balles à pointe creuse causent davantage de dégâts aux tissus, et possèdent une plus grande précision. Tous les archers n'ont pas le talent de Guillaume Tell, capable de viser le cœur d'une pomme d'un trait d'arbalète, et grâce aux fusils et aux lunettes, on effectue des tirs plus précis. Les bunkers abritant des snipers sont tout aussi efficaces contre les morts que contre d'autres types d'ennemis. Le pétrole raffiné et le napalm permettent également de désintégrer les zombies ou des adversaires humains d'une façon encore jamais vue auparavant. De plus, les pièges modernes tirent parti des faiblesses des zombies : inciter une horde zombie à tourner en rond, à la poursuite d'un cerveau ou sur un circuit mécanique comme dans une course de lévriers, peut se révéler bien plus efficace qu'une simple fosse.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Les zombies incarnent l'une des figures les plus populaires de l'horreur. Mais l'image de ces cadavres affamés traînant la patte, et surtout l'idée d'une pandémie mondiale créant des zombies, sont apparues au cours des dernières décennies. Dans de nombreuses traditions folkloriques des Caraïbes, un zombie, ou jumbee, est une catégorie générale désignant un esprit malveillant, s'inspirant de traditions de l'Afrique de l'Ouest. Mais ce fut à Haïti que le zombie prit un nouveau visage, incarnant à lui seul toutes les horreurs de l'esclavage. Pour les Africains vivant comme esclaves dans l'ancienne colonie française de Saint-Domingue, la vie était à peine supportable. Si l'on en croit la tradition, la mort, au moins, promettait la délivrance et le retour au sein d'un paradis africain où les esclaves retrouveraient leur liberté. Mais le suicide, cependant, refermerait cette porte et l'esprit infortuné demeurerait à jamais aux Caraïbes, éternellement esclave : il deviendrait un zombie.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Lors de la révolution haïtienne, le zombie entra dans le folklore local sous la forme d'un serviteur associé à un sorcier malveillant ou, selon certains récits, à un prêtre voudoun (vaudou). Le zombie, hypnotisé ou réanimé, continuait de travailler pour son maître, rappelant ainsi l'épouvantable retour de l'esclavage pour ceux qui avaient lutté pour obtenir et préserver leur liberté. Et ce fut sous cette forme que le zombie fit sa première apparition dans la culture populaire internationale. Les films américains s'emparèrent de la figure du zombie comme symbole d'une magie exotique dans des représentations souvent racistes des Caraïbes, ou simplement pour dépeindre les ''autres'' religions. Ailleurs, les zombies devinrent l'emblème de la peur de se voir déposséder de son propre travail, que ce soit par l'esclavagisme pur et simple, ou métaphoriquement, par les nouvelles formes plus pernicieuses d'exploitation émergeant avec le capitalisme dans des régions comme l'Afrique du Sud.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Cependant, la plupart des gens trouveraient peut-être plus familières les hordes rendues célèbres par George Romero dans son film ''La Nuit des morts-vivants''. Romero y dépeint un monde bouleversé dans lequel les morts qui n'ont pas été enterrés reviennent à la vie. Il est notable que Romero lui-même n'ait jamais utilisé le terme de ''zombie'', lui préférant celui de ''goule'', qui s'inspire plutôt d'un esprit cannibale issu d'une tradition arabe. À la fin du XXe siècle, les zombies devinrent une nouvelle métaphore, incarnant un consumérisme aveugle et déshumanisé, ou bien les peurs de retombées nucléaires, ou encore l'angoisse d'un soulèvement social à grande échelle. Au XXIe siècle, les zombies furent étroitement associés à la peur de la maladie et de l'effondrement de la société. La signification de cette grande figure de l'épouvante se déplaça de la peur de perdre le contrôle de soi-même à un fantasme de survie après que tout semble avoir péri. Les zombies sont alors devenus une force de destruction totale, mais que l'on peut potentiellement tourner à son avantage.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Un aménagement inexploitable de début de partie infligeant des dégâts mineurs et exerçant une zone de contrôle sur les unités hostiles qui traversent cette case ou les cases adjacentes. Construction possible avec une charge de bâtisseur, après avoir découvert l'ingénierie militaire. N'empêche pas le déplacement des unités à travers la case.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Un aménagement inexploitable de partie avancée infligeant des dégâts moyens et exerçant une zone de contrôle sur les unités hostiles qui traversent cette case ou les cases adjacentes. Construction possible avec une charge d'ingénieur militaire, après avoir découvert le rainurage. N'empêche pas le déplacement des unités à travers la case.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Un aménagement inexploitable de début de partie infligeant des dégâts moyens et réduisant les points de mouvement des unités hostiles qui traversent cette case. Conception possible avec une charge de bâtisseur, après avoir découvert la construction. N'empêche pas le déplacement des unités à travers la case.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Un aménagement inexploitable de partie avancée infligeant des dégâts importants et réduisant les points de mouvement des unités hostiles qui traversent cette case. Construction possible avec une charge d'ingénieur militaire, après avoir découvert la balistique. N'empêche pas le déplacement des unités à travers la case.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_RELIGIOUS_DESCRIPTION" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Une fois terminé, octroie le contrôle des zombies actuellement sur le territoire de la ville. Le contrôle dure 15 tours.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_SCIENCE_DESCRIPTION" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Une fois terminé, octroie le contrôle des zombies actuellement sur le territoire de la ville. Le contrôle dure 30 tours.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_DESCRIPTION" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Une unité de combat rapproché hostile ayant une chance d'apparaître sur la carte à l'endroit où une unité a été détruite. Sa puissance de combat augmente à chaque zombie éliminé dans le monde. Si une unité zombie détruit une autre unité, une unité zombie apparaît sur cette case au tour suivant. Si une unité zombie réduit la population d'une ville, une nouvelle unité zombie apparaît sur une case adjacente à la ville. Les zombies ciblent les unités, villes ou quartiers défendables qui se trouvent à proximité.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITCOMMAND_RELEASE_LEVY_DESCRIPTION" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Abandonner le contrôle de l'unité.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITCOMMAND_SPY_SUMMON_ZOMBIES_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Invasion zombie</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITCOMMAND_SPY_SUMMON_ZOMBIES_DESCRIPTION" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Octroie une chance de faire apparaître un zombie sur chaque case exploitée par la ville.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_MESSAGE" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Invasion zombie réussie</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_ENEMY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_MESSAGE" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>L'ennemi a déclenché une invasion zombie</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Inflige des dégâts mineurs et réduit les points de mouvement des unités hostiles qui traversent cette case.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_TRAP" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Inflige des dégâts moyens et réduit les points de mouvement des unités hostiles qui traversent cette case.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_BARRICADE" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Inflige des dégâts mineurs et exerce une zone de contrôle sur les unités hostiles qui traversent cette case ou les cases adjacentes.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TOWERDEFENSE_ZOMBIE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_DESC" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Puissance de mutation +{Property}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_SUMMARY" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>{1_unitName}, votre agent envoyé à {2_CityName}, a réussi à infecter la population et à créer une horde de zombies qui attaque la ville.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_ENEMY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_SUMMARY" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Un espion ennemi a réussi à infecter votre population et à créer une horde de zombies qui menace désormais votre ville, {1_CityName}.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ALCAZAR_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ALCAZAR_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MAORI_PA_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MAORI_PA_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ROMAN_FORT_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ROMAN_FORT_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_FORT_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_FORT_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_VAMPIRE_CASTLE_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_VAMPIRE_CASTLE_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_GREAT_WALL_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_GREAT_WALL_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_BARRICADE}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Zombie|Zombies</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1|2</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Barrikade|Barrikade|Barrikade|Barrikade|Barrikade</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Verstärkte Barrikade|Verstärkte Barrikade|Verstärkten Barrikade|Verstärkten Barrikade|Verstärkte Barrikade</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Falle|Falle|Falle|Falle|Falle</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Moderne Falle|Moderne Falle|Modernen Falle|Modernen Falle|Moderne Falle</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_RELIGIOUS_NAME" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Untotenbekehrung|Untotenbekehrung|Untotenbekehrung|Untotenbekehrung|Untotenbekehrung</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_SCIENCE_NAME" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Dunkles Signal|Dunkle Signal|Dunklen Signal|Dunklen Signals|Dunkle Signal</Text>
      <Gender>neuter</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_CONTENT_TITLE" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Zombie-Verteidigung</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_WELCOME_TITLE" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Willkommen</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_WELCOME_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Mit dem Zombie-Verteidigungsmodus steht Eure Zivilisation einer neuen Bedrohung gegenüber: Die Toten erheben sich. Aus der Asche der Kriege entsteigen Zombies und streifen gierig durch die Länder. Schützt Eure Städte vor diesem tödlichen Fluch – wenigstens noch eine Runde!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_TITLE" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Zombies</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Zombies sind umherstreifende Nahkampfeinheiten. Sie interessieren sich nicht für Eure Städte oder Modernisierungen, doch jede Einheit außerhalb schützender Mauern weckt ihren Jagdtrieb, also haltet die Augen offen, wann immer Ihr Eure Städte verlasst. Sie können Eure Städte auch angreifen und aus einer eliminierten Bevölkerung weitere Zombies machen ...</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_2" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Wenn eine Einheit auf der Karte stirbt, besteht eine geringe Chance, dass sie einige Runden später als Zombie wiederaufersteht. Wenn eine Einheit von einem Zombie vernichtet wird, kommt sie auf jeden Fall in der darauffolgenden Runde als Zombie wieder. Die Bedrohung durch die Untoten wächst aber ständig – mit jedem weltweit getöteten Zombie werden alle übrigen und neuen Zombies immer stärker. Hoffentlich wisst Ihr, worauf Ihr euch einlasst, wenn Ihr gegen die Toten in den Krieg zieht!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_3" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Heilige Stätten und Campusse sind eine zeitweilige Lösung für das Zombieproblem. Durch das Projekt "Untotenbekehrung" bei einer Heiligen Stätte oder das Projekt "Dunkles Signal" bei einem Campus könnt Ihr einige Runden lang die Kontrolle über Zombies innerhalb Eurer Stadtgrenzen übernehmen, und die Horde so gegen Eure Feinde wenden. Achtet nur darauf, dass Ihr in sicherer Entfernung seid, wenn die Kontrolle ausläuft ... oder Ihr sie strategisch sinnvoll aufgebt. Außerdem können Eure Spione den tödlichen Fluch durch die Aktion "Zombie-Ausbruch" zu Euren Feinden bringen.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_TITLE" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Verteidigung</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Eure Ländereien sind der Horde nicht schutzlos ausgeliefert. Zusätzlich zu den Projekten in Heiligen Stätten oder Campusse, können Eure Handwerker Barrikaden oder Fallen errichten, um Eure (lebenden oder toten) Feinde abzuwehren. Barrikaden verursachen geringen Schaden an feindlichen Einheiten, die das Barrikaden-Feld oder angrenzende Felder durchqueren. Fallen verursachen erheblich mehr Schaden, doch nur an feindlichen Einheiten, die sie direkt durchqueren. In späteren Zeitaltern können mächtigere Versionen der Barrikade und der Falle gebaut werden.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_PARA_2" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Diese Konstruktionen können eine starke Verteidigung gegen die wandelnden Toten sein, sind aber auch gegen lebende Rivalen sehr nützlich, da sie jeder Art von Gegner Schaden zufügen. Setzt sie strategisch weise ein, dann erlebt Ihr vielleicht den nächsten Tag.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Das Unheimliche an Zombies ist ihre Ungewissheit. Sind es einfach wiederbelebte Körper oder lebendige Wesen? Die Verteidigung gegen lebende Menschen beruht auf einer Reihe von Faktoren, die keinerlei Auswirkung auf wandelnde Leichen haben: Schmerz, Einschüchterung, Erschöpfung. Stacheldraht kann aber nichts aufhalten, das keinen Schmerz empfindet. Zudem ist die Bewaffnung von Zombies eingeschränkt: Zombies bauen keine Katapulte; sie verschießen keine Pfeile. Daher behandeln Schutzmaßnahmen gegen die Toten diese nicht als denkenden Feind, sondern als sich bewegende Materie – gespitzte Pfähle sollen nicht töten, sondern nur bewegungsunfähig machen, Türme mit Klappleitern bieten Schutz vor Feinden ohne Verstand, die keine Seile hinaufklettern können, Gräben halten Feinde auf, die keine Brücken bauen können. Zumindest solange, bis sich der Graben mit zu vielen von ihnen gefüllt hat.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Die wandelnden Toten kennen keine Erschöpfung. Das ist ihr einziger großer Vorteil – wie ein Meer drücken sie ständig und ohne Unterlass gegen die Barrikaden, die sie aufhalten sollen. Irgendwann geben Mauern aus Holz oder Bambus nach und selbst Mauern aus Feldsteinen bröckeln. Hier kommen moderne Materialien wie verstärkter Beton und Stahl ins Spiel. Genau wie das sternenförmige Fort der Renaissance mit seinen verwinkelten Mauern Kanonenbeschuss abwehren und nicht absorbieren sollte, zielen moderne Verteidigungen darauf ab, die wandelnden Toten abzuwehren, statt sie einfach nur aufzuhalten. Flexible Materialien verbiegen sich, zerbrechen aber dafür nicht an dem unablässigen Druck durch die Toten. Glatte Oberflächen bieten knochigen Fingern keinen Halt und mit Schleusentoren können Gräben ausgespült werden, um zu verhindern, dass Rampen aus Leichenhaufen ältere Formen von Zombie-Verteidigungen überwinden. Dahinter sollten wir sicher sein. Theoretisch.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Mauern sollen Feinde abwehren, Fallen hingegen sollen sie ausschalten, verlangsamen oder bewegungsunfähig machen. Die wandelnden Toten sind vielleicht unnachgiebig, aber nicht gerade schlau. Ein einziger Mensch in einem Turm kann mit seinem saftigen menschlichen Gehirn als Köder dienen, um die Toten – oder feindliche Menschen, die einen "unbewachten" Gegner ausschalten wollen – in die Enge zu locken, wo sie schnell erledigt werden können. Die Untoten auszuschalten beinhaltet allerdings viel mehr, als mit menschlichen Gegnern fertig zu werden. Sie können nicht vertrieben oder tödlich verletzt werden, man muss sie vernichten. Alte Fallen könnten brennendes Pech, verborgene Fallgruben oder einfach Türme voller Bogenschützen sein. Zumindest, bis ihnen die Pfeile ausgehen ...</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Im Verlauf der Jahre haben wir mehr über die untote Bedrohung gelernt. Frühere Fallen bedurften lebender Menschen (freiwillig oder auch nicht) als Köder, aber Ingenieure haben chemische oder tierische Ersatzstoffe entwickelt. Zudem bieten Hohl- oder Personenabwehrgeschosse erhöhten Gewebeschaden und bessere Präzision. Nicht jeder Bogenschütze ist Wilhelm Tell und kann einen Apfel mit einem Armbrustbolzen durchschlagen. Gewehre und Zielvorrichtungen bedeuten präzisere Abschüsse und Bunker mit Scharfschützen funktionieren gegen die Toten genauso gut wie gegen andere Feinde. Raffiniertes Erdöl und Napalm lassen Zombies – oder menschliche Feinde – zu Asche verbrennen, wie es frühere Materialien nicht vermochten. Außerdem zielen moderne Fallen auf die Schwächen der Zombies ab: eine Horde Untoter marschiert endlos im Kreis und jagt ein Gehirn auf einer mechanischen Strecke wie bei einem Hunderennen. Das ist viel wirksamer als eine einfache Grube.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Zombies sind eines der bekanntesten Horror-Klischees geworden. Doch das Bild einer gierigen Horde herumstolpernder Leichname und besonders die Vorstellung einer weltweiten Zombie-Pandemie hat sich erst in den letzten Jahren verbreitet. In vielen karibischen Sagen kommen "Zombie" oder "Jumbie" genannte böse Geister vor, die wiederum von westafrikanischen Traditionen abstammen. In Haiti wurde das Bild des Zombies zu einer Metapher für die Schrecken der Sklaverei. Für die versklavten Afrikaner in der damaligen französischen Kolonie Saint-Domingue war das Leben unerträglich. Der Tod versprach Freiheit und die Rückkehr in ein paradiesisches Afrika, in dem alle frei wären, so lauteten die Sagen. Doch Selbstmord würde diesen Weg versperren und den unseligen Geist für immer versklavt in der Karibik festhalten – als Zombie.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Im Zuge der Haitianischen Revolution wandelte sich das Bild der Zombies zu Dienern eines bösen Zauberers oder Voodoo-Priesters. Die verhexten oder wiedererweckten Zombies dienten weiter ihrem Meister – eine beängstigende Rückkehr zur Sklaverei in einer Gesellschaft, die so hart für ihre Freiheit gekämpft hatte. In dieser Form fanden Zombies zum ersten Mal Eingang in die globale Popkultur. Amerikanische Filme nutzten Zombies als Symbol exotischer Magie in oft rassistischen Darstellungen karibischer oder einfach nur "fremder" Religionen. Andernorts stellten Zombies die Angst vor dem Diebstahl der eigenen Arbeitskraft durch andere dar, ob durch Sklaverei oder als Metapher für die verwirrenden und ausbeuterischen neuen Methoden des Kapitalismus, die in Gegenden wie Südafrika zutage traten.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Doch die Meisten werden Zombiehorden wohl aus dem berühmten Film "Die Nacht der lebenden Toten" von George Romero kennen, in dem die Welt auf den Kopf gestellt wird, als die unbestatteten Toten wieder lebendig werden. Romero verwandte interessanterweise nicht den Begriff "Zombie", sondern nannte die Wesen "Ghule", ein Begriff für arabische Kannibalengeister. Im späten 20. Jahrhundert wurden Zombies zu einer neuen Metapher für geistlosen, seelenlosen Konsumzwang, Ängste vor radioaktivem Niederschlag oder sich bedrohlich abzeichnende soziale Umwälzungen. Im 21. Jahrhundert wurden Zombies mit Furcht vor Krankheiten und dem Zusammenbruch der Gesellschaft assoziiert. Die Angst vor dem Kontrollverlust über sich selbst ist der Vorstellung gewichen, zu überleben während alles andere gestorben ist. Hier sind Zombies eine höchst zerstörerische Kraft, die Ihr möglicherweise zu Eurem Vorteil nutzen könnt.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Eine nicht mehr bearbeitbare frühe Modernisierung, die bei passierenden und angrenzenden feindlichen Einheiten geringen Schaden verursacht und eine Kontrollzone auf sie anwendet. Wird durch Militärtechnik freigeschaltet und kann durch eine Handwerker-Ladung errichtet werden. Verhindert nicht die Fortbewegung über dieses Feld.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Eine nicht mehr bearbeitbare späte Modernisierung, die bei passierenden und angrenzenden feindlichen Einheiten moderaten Schaden verursacht und eine Kontrollzone auf sie anwendet. Wird durch Drall freigeschaltet und kann durch eine Militärpionier-Ladung errichtet werden. Verhindert nicht die Fortbewegung über dieses Feld.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Eine nicht mehr bearbeitbare frühe Modernisierung, die bei passierenden feindlichen Einheiten moderaten Schaden verursacht und sie verlangsamt. Wird durch Bauwesen freigeschaltet und kann durch eine Handwerker-Ladung errichtet werden. Verhindert nicht die Fortbewegung über dieses Feld.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Eine nicht mehr bearbeitbare späte Modernisierung, die bei passierenden feindlichen Einheiten beträchtlichen Schaden verursacht und sie verlangsamt. Wird durch Ballistik freigeschaltet und kann durch eine Militärpionier-Ladung errichtet werden. Verhindert nicht die Fortbewegung über dieses Feld.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_RELIGIOUS_DESCRIPTION" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Bei Fertigstellung stehen die Zombies im Gebiet dieser Stadt unter Eurer Kontrolle. Kontrolle hält 15 Runden lang an.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_SCIENCE_DESCRIPTION" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Bei Fertigstellung stehen die Zombies im Gebiet dieser Stadt unter Eurer Kontrolle. Kontrolle hält 30 Runden lang an.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_DESCRIPTION" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Eine feindliche Nahkampfeinheit, die dort auf der Karte erscheinen kann, wo eine Einheit gestorben ist. Ihre Nahkampfstärke steigt mit jedem auf der Karte ausgelöschten Zombie an. Wenn ein Zombie eine andere Einheit vernichtet, erscheint auf ihrem Todesfeld in der nächsten Runde ein neuer Zombie. Ein neuer Zombie erscheint umgehend in der Nähe der Stadt, sobald ein Zombie ihre Bevölkerung reduziert hat. Zombies suchen sich die nächste Einheit, die nächste Stadt oder den nächsten zu verteidigenden Bezirk in der Nähe als Ziel aus.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITCOMMAND_RELEASE_LEVY_DESCRIPTION" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Gibt die Kontrolle über diese Einheit auf.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITCOMMAND_SPY_SUMMON_ZOMBIES_NAME" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Zombie-Ausbruch</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITCOMMAND_SPY_SUMMON_ZOMBIES_DESCRIPTION" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Bei Erfolg hat jedes bearbeitete Geländefeld dieser Stadt die Chance, dass dort ein Zombie erscheint.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_MESSAGE" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Erfolg: Zombie-Ausbruch verursacht</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_ENEMY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_MESSAGE" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Feind verursachte Zombie-Ausbruch</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Verursacht geringen Schaden bei feindlichen Einheiten, die sich auf dieses Geländefeld begeben, und verlangsamt sie.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_TRAP" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Verursacht moderaten Schaden bei feindlichen Einheiten, die sich auf dieses Geländefeld begeben, und verlangsamt sie.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_BARRICADE" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Verursacht geringen Schaden bei feindlichen Einheiten, die sich auf dieses Geländefeld begeben oder sich in der Nachbarschaft aufhalten, und wendet eine Kontrollzone auf sie an.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TOWERDEFENSE_ZOMBIE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_DESC" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>+{Property} Mutationsstärke</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_SUMMARY" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Euer Agent {1_unitName} in {2_CityName} hat die Bevölkerung erfolgreich infiziert und eine Zombiehorde für den Angriff auf die Stadt erschaffen.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_ENEMY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_SUMMARY" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Ein feindlicher Agent in {1_CityName} hat Eure Bevölkerung erfolgreich infiziert und eine Zombiehorde erschaffen, die nun Eure Stadt bedroht.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ALCAZAR_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ALCAZAR_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MAORI_PA_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MAORI_PA_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ROMAN_FORT_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ROMAN_FORT_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_FORT_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_FORT_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_VAMPIRE_CASTLE_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_VAMPIRE_CASTLE_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_GREAT_WALL_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_GREAT_WALL_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_BARRICADE}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_NAME" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Zombie|Zombie|Zombie|Zombies|Zombie</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Barricata|la Barricata|una Barricata</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Barricata rinforzata|la Barricata rinforzata|una Barricata rinforzata</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Trappola|la Trappola|una Trappola</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Trappola modernizzata|la Trappola modernizzata|una Trappola modernizzata</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_RELIGIOUS_NAME" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Scaccia non-morti</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_SCIENCE_NAME" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Segno Oscuro</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_CONTENT_TITLE" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Difesa dagli zombi</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_WELCOME_TITLE" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Introduzione</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_WELCOME_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>La modalità di gioco Difesa dagli zombi introduce una nuova, pericolosa minaccia per la tua civiltà: i morti che non vogliono restare tali. Gli Zombi si levano dalle ceneri della guerra. Si aggirano in cerca di prede nei tuoi territori e in quelli degli altri, diffondendo la loro letale maledizione. Cerca di impedire che travolgano le tue città... almeno per un altro turno!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_TITLE" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Gli zombi</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Gli Zombi sono unità da mischia che si aggirano nelle lande devastate. Non possono saccheggiare i tuoi miglioramenti: la cosa, in effetti, non gli interessa affatto. D'altro canto, si getteranno immediatamente su qualsiasi unità osi avventurarsi all'esterno, perciò assicurati di tenere sempre gli occhi aperti quando lasci le tue città. Inoltre i non-morti possono anche attaccare le tue città, trasformando la popolazione distrutta in altri zombi...</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_2" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Ogni unità che muore sulla mappa ha una piccola possibilità di tornare come Zombi qualche turno dopo. Tuttavia, le unità uccise dagli Zombi si risvegliano immancabilmente nel turno successivo. La minaccia dei non-morti, comunque, si aggrava sempre più: ogni volta che uno Zombi viene ucciso, in qualsiasi parte del mondo, tutti gli altri Zombi presenti e futuri diventano più forti. Assicurati di renderti ben conto di quello che stai facendo quando vai in guerra contro i morti!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_3" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Luoghi Santi e Campus offrono una soluzione temporanea al problema degli zombi. Attivare il progetto Scaccia non-morti in un Luogo Santo, o il progetto Segno Oscuro in un Campus, ti farà assumere brevemente il controllo degli zombi all'interno del territorio cittadino, il che ti consentirà di rivolgere l'orda contro i tuoi nemici. Assicurati solo di essere ben lontano quando il controllo termina... o quando lo interrompi tu, strategicamente. Inoltre le tue spie possono diffondere l'orribile maledizione attraverso l'azione Epidemia di Zombi.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_TITLE" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Difese</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>I tuoi territori non sono privi di difese contro l'orda. Oltre ai progetti nei Luoghi Santi e nei Campus, i tuoi Costruttori possono creare Barricate e Trappole per respingere i tuoi nemici vivi o morti. Una Barricata infligge una piccola quantità di danni a tutte le unità ostili che la attraversano o entrano in una casella adiacente, mentre una Trappola infligge gravi danni alle unità ostili che la attraversano direttamente. In epoche successive diventa possibile costruire Barricate e Trappole più potenti.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_PARA_2" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Dal momento che infliggono danni a tutti i nemici, rappresentano potenti difese contro i morti viventi ma sono utili anche contro avversari che respirano ancora. Pianifica attentamente il loro uso e potresti anche superare la nottata!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>L'inquietudine suscitata dagli zombi scaturisce dall'ambiguità della loro natura. Sono semplici automi rianimati o si possono ancora considerare creature viventi? Le cose che normalmente spingono le persone a ritirarsi (dolore, paura, fatica) sono semplicemente inutili contro i cadaveri che camminano. Il filo spinato non fa paura a chi non prova alcuna sensazione. Inoltre, le armi degli zombi sono estremamente limitate: i morti non costruiscono trabocchi e non lanciano frecce. Per tutti questi motivi le difese contro i non-morti sono concepite come se dovessero bloccare non un avversario pensante, ma della semplice materia in movimento: le picche appuntite non sono piazzate per uccidere, ma per immobilizzare; una torre con una scaletta mobile è un riparo adeguato contro un nemico che non ha cervello sufficiente per scalare una fune; un fossato è in grado di respingere un'orda incapace di costruire un ponte. Almeno finché i morti non diventano troppo numerosi.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>I morti viventi non si stancano mai. È questo il loro grande vantaggio: come onde del mare, si abbattono senza tregua sulle difese erette per respingerli. A un certo punto le pareti di legno e bambù cedono, e anche le mura di pietra grezza sono destinate a sgretolarsi. È qui che entrano in gioco i materiali moderni: il cemento armato, l'acciaio. Proprio come i forti del Rinascimento, grazie alla loro forma a stella, erano progettati per deviare anziché assorbire l'urto delle palle di cannone, così le difese moderne tendono a incanalare i morti viventi anziché bloccarli sul posto. I materiali flessibili si piegano ma non si spezzano quando i morti premono incessantemente su di essi. Le superfici lisce non offrono presa alle dita scorticate, mentre dighe e paratie mobili permettono di svuotare fossati e trincee, impedendo la formazione delle alte pile di cadaveri che avrebbero permesso di superare i vecchi sistemi di difesa anti-zombi. Dietro a queste protezioni dovremmo essere salvi. Dovremmo.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Mentre le mura sono un tipo di difesa che punta a tenere i nemici all'esterno, le trappole hanno lo scopo di eliminarli, rallentarli o immobilizzarli. Se da un lato i morti viventi sono implacabili nella loro avanzata, dall'altro non sono molto intelligenti. Un singolo essere umano in una torre, con il suo succulento cervello, è un'esca sufficiente per attirare i morti (o umani ostili desiderosi di eliminare un nemico "inerme") in uno spazio chiuso in cui possono essere eliminati facilmente. Ma i morti sono molto più difficili da sconfiggere definitivamente degli essere umani. Non possono essere scacciati né feriti; devono essere distrutti. Nell'antichità le trappole potevano essere costituite da pece bollente, pozzi nascosti o semplici torri piene di arcieri. Almeno finché duravano le frecce...</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Col passare degli anni, abbiamo imparato molto sulla minaccia dei non-morti. Le prime trappole richiedevano l'uso di umani vivi (volontari o no) come esca, ma i nostri ingegneri hanno sviluppato sostituti chimici o animali. Inoltre, i proiettili a punta cava e anti-persona sono in grado di infliggere danni maggiori ai tessuti, con più precisione. Non tutti gli arcieri sono Guglielmo Tell, in grado di colpire in pieno una mela con una balestra: a questo ci ha pensato la rigatura delle canne e l'adozione dei mirini telescopici, che hanno aumentato la frequenza delle uccisioni di precisione. I bunker e i cecchini sono altrettanto efficaci contro i morti come con tutti gli altri. La raffinazione del petrolio e il napalm hanno permesso di disintegrare gli zombi (e i nemici umani) in un modo che con i precedenti materiali sarebbe stato impossibile. Oltre a tutto questo, le trappole moderne sfruttano i punti deboli degli zombi: orde di non-morti che marciano in circolo senza fine, inseguendo un cervello su una pista meccanica come cani da corsa intorno a un circuito, sono una soluzione molto più efficace di un semplice pozzo scavato nella terra.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Gli zombi sono tra i più famosi protagonisti del genere horror. Ma l'immagine dei cadaveri semoventi affamati, e soprattutto l'idea di una pandemia globale di non-morti, si è diffusa solo in anni recenti. Nel folklore caraibico quella dello zombi o "jumbee" è una categoria generale di spiriti maligni che affonda le radici nella tradizione dell'Africa occidentale. È ad Haiti che lo zombi è diventato qualcosa di completamente diverso: una metafora per tutti gli orrori della schiavitù. Per gli schiavi africani di Santo Domingo, che allora era una colonia francese, la vita era quasi intollerabile. La morte, quanto meno, prometteva una liberazione e, così raccontavano le leggende, un ritorno in un paradiso in Africa dove finalmente avrebbero potuto essere liberi. Ma il suicidio avrebbe chiuso questa porta e lo sfortunato spirito sarebbe rimasto per sempre nei Caraibi, schiavo per l'eternità... Uno zombi.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Dopo la rivoluzione haitiana lo zombi entrò nel folklore locale come servo di uno stregone maligno o, in alcune versioni, di un sacerdote vudun (voodoo). Lo zombi, ridotto in servitù da uno stato di trance o rianimato, continuava a lavorare per il padrone, evocando così un orribile ritorno alla schiavitù per un popolo che aveva lottato duramente per guadagnare e conservare la libertà. In effetti, i primi zombi a entrare nella cultura popolare globale appartenevano alla prima categoria. Nei film americani gli zombi simboleggiavano una magia esotica nelle rappresentazioni, spesso razziste, dei Caraibi o semplicemente delle religioni "altre". In altri luoghi gli zombi divennero la rappresentazione della paura di vedersi sottratto il lavoro da un ritorno esplicito dello schiavismo o, in via metaforica, da un capitalismo che si manifestava in nuove forme confuse e caratterizzate dallo sfruttamento in regioni come il Sudafrica.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Ma la maggior parte delle persone conosce più che altro le orde rese famose da George Romero nel suo film "La notte dei morti viventi". Qui Romero ci presenta un mondo completamente rovesciato, in cui i morti insepolti tornano alla vita. È da notare che Romero non usa mai il termine "zombi", ma piuttosto "ghoul", a sua volta un riferimento a uno spirito cannibale della tradizione araba. Alla fine del XX secolo gli zombi hanno cominciato a esprimere altre metafore, diventando la manifestazione di un consumismo privo di senso e d'anima, del timore della catastrofe nucleare o della minaccia di una colossale sollevazione sociale. Nel XXI secolo gli zombi sono fortemente associati alla paura della malattia e del collasso della società. Il nucleo dell'orrore è mutato, passando dalla paura di perdere il controllo su di sé alla fantasia di sopravvivere dopo che tutti gli altri sono morti. In questo gioco gli zombi sono una forza totalmente distruttiva, che però i giocatori possono, potenzialmente, sfruttare a proprio vantaggio.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Un miglioramento che impedisce lo sfruttamento della casella ed è disponibile già nelle prime fasi della partita. Infligge una piccola quantità di danni ed esercita una Zona di Controllo sulle unità ostili che l'attraversano o entrano in una casella adiacente. Sbloccato dalla scoperta dell'Ingegneria Militare, la sua creazione richiede una carica dei Costruttori. Non impedisce alle unità di attraversare la casella.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Un miglioramento che impedisce lo sfruttamento della casella ed è disponibile nelle fasi avanzate della partita. Infligge una quantità media di danni ed esercita una Zona di Controllo sulle unità ostili che l'attraversano o entrano in una casella adiacente. Sbloccato dalla scoperta della Rigatura delle Canne, la sua creazione richiede una carica di un Ingegnere militare. Non impedisce alle unità di attraversare la casella.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Un miglioramento che impedisce lo sfruttamento della casella ed è disponibile già nelle prime fasi della partita. Infligge una quantità media di danni ed esaurisce il movimento delle unità ostili che l'attraversano direttamente. Sbloccato dalla scoperta della Costruzione, la sua creazione richiede una carica dei Costruttori. Non impedisce alle unità di attraversare la casella.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Un miglioramento che impedisce lo sfruttamento della casella ed è disponibile nelle fasi avanzate della partita. Infligge una grande quantità di danni ed esaurisce il movimento delle unità ostili che l'attraversano direttamente. Sbloccato dalla scoperta della Balistica, la sua creazione richiede una carica di un Ingegnere militare. Non impedisce alle unità di attraversare la casella.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_RELIGIOUS_DESCRIPTION" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Al completamento ottieni il controllo degli zombi che in quel momento si trovano all'interno del territorio della città. Il controllo dura 15 turni.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_SCIENCE_DESCRIPTION" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Al completamento ottieni il controllo degli zombi che in quel momento si trovano all'interno del territorio della città. Il controllo dura 30 turni.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_DESCRIPTION" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Un'unità da mischia ostile che ha una certa probabilità di apparire sulla mappa nella casella in cui è morta un'unità. La sua Forza di combattimento in mischia aumenta con ogni zombi eliminato dal gioco a livello globale. Se uno Zombi distrugge un'altra unità, un nuovo Zombi compare in quella casella nel turno successivo. Se uno Zombi riduce la popolazione di una città, un nuovo Zombi compare immediatamente accanto alla città stessa. Gli Zombi prendono di mira l'unità, la città o il distretto difendibile più vicini.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITCOMMAND_RELEASE_LEVY_DESCRIPTION" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Interrompi il controllo di quest'unità.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITCOMMAND_SPY_SUMMON_ZOMBIES_NAME" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Epidemia di Zombi</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITCOMMAND_SPY_SUMMON_ZOMBIES_DESCRIPTION" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Al completamento ha la possibilità di far comparire uno Zombi per ogni casella sfruttata da questa città.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_MESSAGE" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Prodotta con successo un'Epidemia di Zombi</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_ENEMY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_MESSAGE" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Il nemico ha causato un'Epidemia di Zombi</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Infligge una piccola quantità di danni ed esaurisce il movimento delle unità ostili che l'attraversano direttamente.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_TRAP" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Infligge una quantità media di danni ed esaurisce il movimento delle unità ostili che l'attraversano direttamente.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_BARRICADE" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Infligge una piccola quantità di danni ed esercita una Zona di Controllo sulle unità ostili che l'attraversano o entrano in una casella adiacente.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TOWERDEFENSE_ZOMBIE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_DESC" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>+{Property} Forza di mutazione</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_SUMMARY" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Il tuo agente {1_unitName} a {2_CityName} ha infettato con successo la popolazione, creando un'Orda zombi per attaccare la città.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_ENEMY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_SUMMARY" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Una spia nemica nella città di {1_CityName} ha infettato con successo la popolazione, creando un'Orda zombi che ora minaccia la città.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ALCAZAR_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ALCAZAR_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MAORI_PA_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MAORI_PA_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ROMAN_FORT_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ROMAN_FORT_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_FORT_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_FORT_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_VAMPIRE_CASTLE_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_VAMPIRE_CASTLE_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_GREAT_WALL_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_GREAT_WALL_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_BARRICADE}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_NAME" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Zombi|uno Zombi|dal tuo Zombi|al tuo Zombi|il tuo Zombi|da uno Zombi</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>バリケード</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>強化バリケード</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>罠</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>近代的な罠</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_RELIGIOUS_NAME" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>悪霊退散</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_SCIENCE_NAME" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>闇の信号</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_CONTENT_TITLE" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>ゾンビ撃退</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_WELCOME_TITLE" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>ようこそ</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_WELCOME_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>「ゾンビ撃退」モードでは、文明を脅かす脅威として動きまわる死者が登場します。戦いで命を落とした者たちがゾンビとなって甦り、プレイヤーの土地を餌食にしながら恐るべき呪いを周囲に撒き散らします。押し寄せるゾンビたちから1ターンでも長く都市を守りましょう！
</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_TITLE" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>ゾンビ</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>ゾンビは荒野をさまよう近接戦闘ユニットです。施設の略奪はできません。そうしたことにはまったく興味がないのです。しかし、都市の外をうろつく者に出会うと即座に追いかけてくるので、都市を離れる場合は注意が必要です。また、都市を襲うこともあり、殺された人々はゾンビになってしまいます。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_2" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>マップ上で死亡したユニットは、数ターン後にゾンビ・ユニットとして甦る可能性がありますが、その確率は高くはありません。一方、ゾンビによって倒されたユニットは、次ターンに必ずゾンビとして復活します。亡者の脅威は着実に増していきます。なぜなら、世界のどこかでゾンビが倒されるたびに、その時点で存在するゾンビやその後に生まれるゾンビは強さが増していくからです。死者との戦いを始めるのは、自分が何をしようとしているのかしっかり理解してからにしましょう！</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_3" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>聖地やキャンパスは、ゾンビの群れに対する一時的な解決策となります。聖地での「悪霊退散」プロジェクトやキャンパスでの「闇の信号」プロジェクトを実施すると、短期間ですが都市の境界内にいるゾンビを支配下に置くことができます。これにより、ゾンビの群れに敵を襲わせることもできます、支配の効果が切れる前に (あるいは何か意図があって自ら支配を解く前に) ゾンビを遠ざけておくことをお忘れなく。スパイに「ゾンビ大発生」を実行させ、この恐るべき呪いを敵地で発生させることも可能です。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_TITLE" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>撃退</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>ゾンビの群れから領土を守る手段がないわけではありません。聖地やキャンパスでのプロジェクトに加え、労働者にバリケードや罠を作らせれば、敵 (生きているか否かにかかわらず) を退けるのに役立つことでしょう。バリケードは、そこや隣接タイルを通過した敵ユニットに少々のダメージを与えます。罠は、そこを通過した敵ユニットに大ダメージを与えます。時代が進むと、より強力なバリケードや罠を作ることが可能になります。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_PARA_2" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>バリケードや罠は、ゾンビに対して抜群の防御力を発揮しますが、敵の種類に関係なくダメージを与えられるので、もっと「生き生き」した敵に対しても有効です。巧みに設置すれば、きっと明日の朝日を拝むことができるでしょう。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>ゾンビの不気味な点は、その正体がよくわからないことにある。動くだけの単なる物体なのだろうか？ それともある種の生命体なのだろうか？ 痛み、威嚇、疲労。人間に対しては有効なこれらの防衛手段は、歩く死体にはまったく通用しない。痛みを感じない者に対して有刺鉄線が何の役に立つだろう？ 一方、ゾンビが使う武器は限られており、投石機を作ることも、弓から矢を放つこともできない。そのため、死者に対する防衛策を講じる際は、相手を思考する敵ではなく動く物体として扱うことが重要となる。鋭くとがらせた棒は、殺すためではなく動きを止めるために使われる。収納可能な梯子がある塔は、ロープをよじ登る知恵を持たない敵から避難するのに有効だ。水路は橋を作れない敵を封じ込めるのに役立つだろう。ただし、すべてはゾンビの数が圧倒的ではないことが前提だ。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>歩く死者は疲れを知らない。これは彼らの大きな強みの1つだ。まるで波のように、彼らは防壁に向かって絶え間なく押し寄せてくる。彼らの前には木や竹はもちろん、石で築かれた壁さえ最後には崩れ落ちてしまう。ここで活躍するのが近代の素材である鉄筋コンクリートや鋼鉄である。ルネサンス期の星形要塞の壁が、砲弾を受け止めるのではなく逸らすために斜めになっていたのと同じように、現代の防衛施設は死者を足止めすることではなく進路を逸らすことを重視している。弾力性に富む素材は、死者が執拗に押し寄せてきても曲がるだけで決して折れない。滑らかな表面は骨が露出した指ではつかめず、水門を使って溝や堀に水を流せば文字どおり死者たちを一掃することが可能だ (倒したゾンビをそのままにしておくと、死体が積み重なり、やがてはそれをよじ登って防衛施設内へ入りこまれてしまう)。こうした壁の背後にいれば安全だ。安全なはずなのだ。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>壁が敵の侵入を防ぐことを目的とするのに対し、罠は敵の排除や足止め、拘束を目的としている。また、歩く死者たちは執拗だが賢くはない。生きた人間が1人塔にたてこもっているだけでも、死者 (あるいは「無防備な」相手を襲おうとする人間) を対処可能な距離までおびき寄せるには事足りる。しかし死者を始末するのは、人間の相手をするより多くの手間がかかる。たとえ致命傷を負っても死者は逃げないので、完全に倒す以外に方法がないからだ。太古の罠としては、火のついたコールタール、落とし穴、弓兵を配置した塔などがあるが、矢が尽きたら一巻の終わりだ…</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>歳月を重ねるにつれ、我々は亡者の脅威について多くの知識を得た。初期の罠は生きている人間 (志願した者もいたし、そうでない者もいた) を囮に使っていたが、今では科学者たちが作った化学物質や動物がその代用品として使われている。また、ホロ―ポイント弾や対人弾を使えば、ゾンビの体組織により大きなダメージを、より正確に与えることができる。弓兵すべてがウィリアム・テルのようにリンゴをクロスボウで射ぬけるわけではない。しかし、銃身のライフリング加工や照準器によって命中率は大幅に向上した。狙撃兵を配置したトーチカは、通常の敵だけでなく死者に対しても有効だ。石油の精製物やナパームは、ゾンビ (あるいは人間の敵) を従来の燃焼物では不可能なレベルまで焼きつくすことができる。加えて、今はゾンビの弱点を突く罠もある。コンベアに脳みそを乗せ、それを亡者たちに追いかけさせれば、奴らはドッグレースの犬のように、ひたすらグルグルと歩きつづける。単なる落とし穴よりはるかに効果的だ。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>今やゾンビはホラー作品の題材として知らぬ者のない存在になっている。しかし、足を引きずりながら歩く食欲旺盛な死体というイメージや、亡者が世界各地で大発生するというコンセプトは、近年になって生まれたものにすぎない。カリブ海地域の民間伝承には、ゾンビ (ジャンビーとも呼ばれる) を悪霊の一種としているものが多い。こうした考え方自体は西アフリカ発祥のものだが、ゾンビはハイチで姿を変え、奴隷制度のあらゆる恐怖を代弁する存在となった。当時フランスの植民地だったサン＝ドマングで奴隷として扱われていたアフリカ人にとって、人生は耐え難いほど辛いものだった。そんな彼らにしてみれば、ある意味において死は解放であり、アフリカにあるとされていた楽園への帰還の希望であった。しかし、自ら死を選ぶとこの扉は閉ざされ、不幸な霊はいつまでもカリブ海へ留まらなければならないと考えられていた。永遠の奴隷、ゾンビとなって。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>ハイチ革命の後、ゾンビは悪い魔法使い、あるいはブドゥン (ブードゥー教) の司祭のしもべとして現地の民間伝承に入り込んだ。ゾンビは、夢遊病のような状態にされた人間や操られている死体で、主人のために働きつづけるとされた。これは、自由を目指して必死に戦ってきた人々からすると、過酷な奴隷労働の日々への逆戻りを連想させるものだった。実際、世界的なポップカルチャーに初めて登場したときのゾンビは、このような存在だった。アメリカ映画は、異国の魔術のシンボルとしてゾンビを用いたが、そうした作品にはカリブ海や「他の」宗教を人種差別的な視点で描いたものが多かった。他の地域では、ゾンビは奴隷制の復活や南アフリカなどの地域で台頭していた複雑で搾取的な新たな形の資本主義によって仕事が奪われることへ恐れの隠喩として描かれた。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>しかし、ほとんどの人がゾンビと聞いて思い浮かべるのは、ジョージ・ロメロ監督の映画『ナイト・オブ・ザ・リビング・デッド』で描かれた死者の大群だろう。この作品でロメロは、死者が蘇ることで大混乱に陥った世界を描いた。ロメロがこの作品の中で「ゾンビ」という言葉を一度も使っていないことは注目に値するだろう。この作品において人外の存在は「グール」と呼ばれていた。グールとはアラビアの伝承に登場する人食いの悪鬼のことである。20世紀末になるとゾンビは新たなメタファーとなり、心も魂も持たない大量消費主義の化身、核戦争に対する恐怖、社会的な大変動の象徴として描かれることが増えた。21世紀に入ってからは、疫病や社会の崩壊への懸念と密接に結び付けられるようになった。恐怖の源泉は、自分が自分ではなくなってしまうことへの恐れから、自分以外のあらゆるものが死に絶えた後も生きつづけねばならないという悪夢へと変化した。このゲームモードのゾンビは、純然たる破壊の権化である。しかし、うまく利用すれば、ライバルに対する有効な武器に転じることも不可能ではない、かもしれない。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>支配領域を持ち、建設されたタイルや隣接タイルを通過する敵ユニットに若干のダメージを与える、活用できない初期の施設。「軍事工学」によって解除され、労働者の労働力を1使って建設される。通行するユニットの移動は妨げない。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>支配領域を持ち、建設されたタイルや隣接タイルを通過した敵ユニットに中程度のダメージを与える、活用できない後の時代の施設。「ライフリング」で解除され、工兵の労働力を1使って建設される。通行するユニットの移動は妨げない。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>建設されたタイルを通過した敵ユニットに中程度のダメージを与え、移動力を低下させる、活用できない初期の施設。「建築学」で解除され、労働者の労働力を1使って建設される。通行するユニットの移動は妨げない。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>建設されたタイルを通過した敵ユニットに大ダメージを与え、移動力を低下させる、活用できない後の時代の施設。「弾道学」で解除され、工兵の労働力を1使って建設される。通行するユニットの移動は妨げない。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_RELIGIOUS_DESCRIPTION" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>完了すると、その時点でこの都市の領域内にいるゾンビを支配できる。支配は15ターン持続する。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_SCIENCE_DESCRIPTION" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>完了すると、その時点でこの都市の領域内にいるゾンビを支配できる。支配は30ターン持続する。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_DESCRIPTION" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>マップ上でユニットが倒されると、一定の確率で敵対的な近接攻撃ユニットが同じ場所に現れる。このユニットの近接戦闘力は、世界全体で倒されたゾンビの数に応じて増加する。ゾンビにユニットが倒されると、次のターンに新しいゾンビ・ユニットが同じ場所に出現する。ゾンビが都市の人口を減らした場合、新しいゾンビ・ユニットが都市の隣に即座に出現する。ゾンビは最も近くにいるユニットや都市、防御可能な区域を狙う。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITCOMMAND_RELEASE_LEVY_DESCRIPTION" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>このユニットを支配から解放する。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITCOMMAND_SPY_SUMMON_ZOMBIES_NAME" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>ゾンビ大発生</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITCOMMAND_SPY_SUMMON_ZOMBIES_DESCRIPTION" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>完了すると、この都市によって活用された各タイルに一定確率でゾンビが発生する。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_MESSAGE" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>ゾンビを大発生させることに成功した</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_ENEMY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_MESSAGE" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>敵がゾンビを大発生させた</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>このタイルに進入した敵ユニットに若干のダメージを与え、移動力を低下させる。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_TRAP" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>このタイルに進入した敵ユニットに中程度のダメージを与え、移動力を低下させる。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_BARRICADE" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>支配領域を持ち、このタイルや周囲タイルに進入した敵ユニットに若干のダメージを与える。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TOWERDEFENSE_ZOMBIE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_DESC" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>変異による戦闘力+{Property}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_SUMMARY" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>我々の工作員である{1_unitName}によって{2_CityName}市民の間に感染が広まり、今や街はゾンビの群れに襲われています。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_ENEMY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_SUMMARY" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>敵スパイの策略により、{1_CityName}でゾンビの群れが発生しました。市民が次々に感染しており、このままでは街が危険です。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ALCAZAR_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ALCAZAR_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MAORI_PA_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MAORI_PA_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ROMAN_FORT_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ROMAN_FORT_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_FORT_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_FORT_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_VAMPIRE_CASTLE_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_VAMPIRE_CASTLE_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_GREAT_WALL_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_GREAT_WALL_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_BARRICADE}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_NAME" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>ゾンビ</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>바리케이드</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>강화된 바리케이드</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>함정</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>현대화된 함정</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_RELIGIOUS_NAME" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>언데드화</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_SCIENCE_NAME" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>검은 신호</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_CONTENT_TITLE" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>좀비 방어</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_WELCOME_TITLE" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>환영합니다</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_WELCOME_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>좀비 방어 게임 모드에서는 여러분의 문명을 위협하는 새로운 존재가 등장합니다: 이제 죽은 자가 다시 일어납니다! 좀비들은 전쟁의 잿더미에서 일어날 수 있으며, 여러분과 다른 문명의 대지를 공격하며 치명적인 바이러스를 퍼뜨립니다. 좀비 떼가 도시를 뒤덮지 못하도록, 한 턴이라도 더 막아야 합니다!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_TITLE" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>좀비</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>좀비는 황무지를 배회하는 근접 유닛으로, 시설을 약탈할 수 없습니다. 사실 이러한 것에는 별로 관심이 없습니다. 하지만 외부에서 방황하는 유닛을 발견하면 즉시 뒤쫓아가기 때문에 도시를 떠날 때는 항상 주위를 잘 살피시기 바랍니다. 좀비는 도시를 공격하고 사람들을 해쳐 좀비를 더 많이 발생시킬 수도 있습니다...</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_2" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>유닛이 지도 상에서 죽으면 낮은 확률로 몇 턴 후 좀비로 부활할 수 있습니다. 하지만 유닛이 좀비에게 죽으면 반드시 다음 턴에 좀비로 부활합니다. 좀비 떼의 위협은 지속적으로 커집니다. 어디에서든 좀비가 죽을 때마다 남은 좀비와 새로운 좀비가 점점 더 강력해지기 때문입니다. 좀비 떼와 전투를 벌일 때는 단단히 대비하세요!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_3" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>성지와 캠퍼스는 좀비 떼에 대한 임시 해결책을 보유하고 있습니다. 성지에서 언데드화 프로젝트를 사용하거나, 캠퍼스에서 검은 신호 프로젝트를 사용하면 도시 경계 내에서 좀비 떼를 일시적으로 조종할 수 있습니다. 즉 좀비 떼가 적을 공격하도록 만들 수 있습니다. 단, 조종 시간이 만료되거나, 조종을 전략적으로 종료했을 경우 좀비 떼에게서 충분히 멀리 떨어져 있어야 합니다. 또한 스파이는 좀비 창궐 행동으로 적들에게 치명적인 저주를 퍼뜨릴 수 있습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_TITLE" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>방어</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>좀비 떼를 막을 방법이 아예 없는 것은 아닙니다. 성지와 캠퍼스에서 프로젝트를 진행하는 것 이외에도 건설자는 바리케이드나 함정을 만들어 (살아있든 죽었든)적을 막을 수 있습니다. 바리케이드는 통과하는 적 유닛이나 인접한 타일에 경미한 피해를 입히고, 함정은 직접 통과하는 적 유닛에 막대한 피해를 입힙니다. 이후 시대에서 더욱 강력한 바리케이드나 함정을 만들 수도 있습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_PARA_2" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>이러한 방어 장치들은 좀비들을 매우 효과적으로 막을 수 있지만, 모든 종류의 적들에게 피해를 주기 때문에 살아 있는 적들을 대상으로도 유용합니다. 전략적으로 잘 활용한다면 밤을 무사히 넘길지도 모릅니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>좀비의 기괴함은 바로 모호함에서 비롯됩니다. 좀비는 단지 움직이는 물체일까요, 아니면 생명체의 일종 일까요? 인간 유형의 적들을 막는 데 사용되는 고통, 위협, 피로 등은 좀비에게 적용되지 않습니다. 가시철조망은 고통을 느끼지 못하는 대상에게는 아무 소용도 없습니다. 또한 좀비의 무기는 제한적입니다. 좀비는 투석기를 만들거나 화살을 발사하지 않습니다. 따라서 좀비를 방어할 때는 좀비를 생각하는 적이 아니라 움직이는 물체로 간주해야 합니다. 날카로운 막대기로 좀비를 죽이지는 못해도 움직이지 못하게 만들 수는 있으며, 접이식 사다리가 있는 탑은 밧줄을 탈 줄 모르는 좀비로부터 안전한 피난처가 되고, 참호는 다리를 만들 줄 모르는 좀비들을 봉쇄할 수 있습니다. 물론 좀비가 너무 많아지면 곤란해질 수 있습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>좀비는 지치지 않으며, 이는 좀비의 매우 큰 무기입니다. 좀비 떼는 구축된 방어막을 마치 바다와 같이 끊임없이 밀어붙입니다. 결국에는 나무와 대나무 조각으로 만들어진 장벽과 심지어 석벽이 무너집니다. 여기서 현대 자재인 철근 콘크리트와 강철이 중요해집니다. 르네상스 시대의 성형 요새가 각진 벽을 건설하여, 포탄의 충격을 흡수하는 대신 빗겨 나가게 만든 것처럼, 현대 방어 시설도 좀비 떼를 단순히 막기보다는 다른 곳을 향하도록 만드는 데 초점을 맞춥니다. 유연한 소재는 좀비 떼가 아무리 몰아쳐도 구부러질 뿐 부서지지는 않습니다. 앙상한 손으로는 매끄러운 표면을 잡을 수 없고, 수문은 참호와 해자를 씻어내어 좀비 떼가 쌓인 시체 더미를 넘고 방어선을 넘어오지 못하도록 만듭니다. 이러한 방어선 뒤에서 우리는 안전할 것입니다. 그래야만 합니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>벽은 좀비들을 막는 데 사용되는 방어 장치이지만, 함정은 좀비들을 제거, 둔화시키거나 움직이지 못하게 만드는 데 사용됩니다. 좀비들은 무자비하긴 해도 영리하지는 않습니다. 탑에 맛있어 보이는 뇌를 가진 사람 한 명을 배치하여 좀비 떼 또는 '비무장' 상대를 제거하려는 적을 함정으로 가까이 유인하여 처치할 수 있습니다. 하지만 좀비를 상대하는 것은 인간 적들을 상대하는 것보다 훨씬 어렵습니다. 좀비는 쫓아내거나 치명상을 입힐 수 없기 때문에 완전히 파괴해야 합니다. 고대 함정으로는 불타는 역청, 숨겨진 구덩이, 궁수들이 숨어 있는 탑이 있습니다. 물론, 화살이 바닥나기 전까지만 유효합니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>세월이 흐르면서 우리는 좀비의 위협에 대해 더 자세히 알게 되었습니다. 이전에는 (자원자든 아니든)살아 있는 인간을 미끼로 사용하는 함정을 건설했지만, 이후 공학자들은 화학물질이나 동물을 미끼로 사용하는 함정을 개발했습니다. 또한 HP탄환이나 대인 탄환은 좀비의 생체 조직에 더 큰 피해를 주고 정확도를 높였습니다. 모든 궁수가 윌리엄 텔은 아니며 석궁 화살로 사과를 명중시킬 수는 없습니다. 대신 조준경과 강선을 사용하면 좀비를 더욱 정확하게 '처치'할 수 있습니다. 벙커에 저격수를 배치하는 방식 역시 다른 적과 마찬가지로 좀비에게도 효과적입니다. 또한 정제된 석유와 네이팜은 과거의 화학물질과 달리 좀비나 인간 적들을 완전히 녹여버립니다. 또한 현대의 함정은 좀비의 약점을 이용합니다. 좀비 떼가 개 경주장처럼 기계식 트랙에 놓인 뇌를 쫓아가며 원 모양으로 계속 돌도록 만드는 방식이 단순한 구덩이보다 훨씬 더 효과적일 수 있습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>좀비는 이제 공포물의 대명사가 되었습니다. 하지만 게걸스럽고 느릿느릿 걷는 시체의 이미지와 좀비 바이러스가 전 세계로 퍼진다는 아이디어는 비교적 최근에 생겨났습니다. 많은 카리브해 민속 전통에서 좀비 또는 점비(jumbee)는 서아프리카 전통에서 유래한 일반적 유형의 악령입니다. 하지만 아이티에서 좀비는 노예생활의 공포를 형상화한 존재가 되었습니다. 당시 프랑스 식민지 생도맹그에 살던 아프리카 노예들의 삶은 매우 비참했습니다. 적어도 죽음은 해방을 약속하고 자유를 누릴 수 있는 아프리카 낙원으로 돌아갈 수 있도록 해주었지만, 자살할 경우에는 이러한 문이 닫히고 카리브해에 영원히 갇힌 채 영원한 노예, 즉 좀비가 됩니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>아이티 혁명 이후 좀비는 지역 민속에서 사악한 마법사의 하인 또는 일부 설화에서는 부두 사제로 등장했습니다. 마법에 걸리거나 부활한 좀비는 주인을 위해 계속 일했고, 이는 자유를 얻기 위해 싸우던 사람들에게는 끔찍한 노예 제도의 귀환을 떠올리게 만들었습니다. 실제로 좀비는 앞에 언급한 첫 번째 의미로 글로벌 대중 문화에 등장했습니다. 미국 영화는 좀비를 이국적인 마법의 상징물로 사용하였는데, 이러한 모습은 카리브해 또는 '기타' 종교에 대한 인종차별적 묘사로 비춰지기도 했습니다. 다른 지역에서 좀비는 끔찍한 노예 제도의 귀환으로 노동력을 빼앗긴 공포의 존재로 나타나거나, 남아프리카 등의 지역에서 새로운 유형의 자본주의가 보여준 혼란스럽고 착취적인 방식에 대한 은유로 등장했습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>많은 사람은 조지 로메로 감독의 영화 '살아있는 시체들의 밤'에 나와 유명해진 좀비의 모습에 익숙합니다. 이 영화에서 로메로 감독은 묻히지 않은 시체들이 다시 살아나 사람들을 공격하는 세상을 묘사했습니다. 로메로 감독은 '좀비'라는 용어 대신 아랍의 식인 영혼을 나타내는 '구울'이라는 용어를 사용했습니다. 20세기 후반 좀비는 무의미하고 영혼 없는 소비주의, 핵폭발에 대한 두려움, 대규모 사회적 격변에 대한 새로운 은유로 사용되었습니다. 21세기에 좀비는 질병과 사회 붕괴에 대한 두려움과 밀접한 관련이 있습니다. 공포의 중심은 자신에 대한 통제력을 잃는다는 두려움에서 모두 죽고 혼자 살아남는 판타지적 세상으로 바뀌었습니다. 문명에 등장하는 좀비는 무지막지하게 파괴적인 존재입니다. 하지만 이러한 파괴력을 역이용할 수도 있습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>위를 직접 지나가거나 인접한 적 유닛에게 약간의 피해를 입히고 통제 지역 영향력을 행사하는 운용 불가능한 초기 시대 시설입니다. 군사 공학으로 잠금 해제되고 건설자 횟수를 소모하여 건설됩니다. 이 공간을 지나는 유닛 이동을 막지 않습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>위를 직접 지나가거나 인접한 적 유닛에게 보통 수준의 피해를 입히고 통제 지역 영향력을 행사하는 운용 불가능한 후기 시대 시설입니다. 강선으로 잠금 해제되고 공병 횟수를 소모하여 건설됩니다. 이 공간을 지나는 유닛 이동을 막지 않습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>위를 직접 지나가는 적 유닛에게 중간 정도의 피해를 입히고 이동력을 고갈시키는 운용 불가능한 초기 시대 시설입니다. 건축으로 잠금 해제되고 건설자 횟수를 소모하여 건설됩니다. 이 공간을 지나는 유닛 이동을 막지 않습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>위를 직접 지나가는 적 유닛에게 막대한 피해를 입히고 이동력을 고갈시키는 운용 불가능한 후기 시대 시설입니다. 탄도학으로 잠금 해제되고 공병 횟수를 소모하여 건설됩니다. 이 공간을 통과하는 유닛 이동을 막지 않습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_RELIGIOUS_DESCRIPTION" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>완료하면 현재 이 도시 영토에 있는 좀비를 조종할 수 있습니다. 조종은 15턴 동안 지속됩니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_SCIENCE_DESCRIPTION" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>완료하면 현재 이 도시 영토에 있는 좀비를 조종할 수 있습니다. 조종은 30턴 동안 지속됩니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_DESCRIPTION" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>유닛이 죽은 위치에 생성될 가능성이 있는 적대적인 근접 유닛입니다. 전 세계에서 좀비가 제거될 때마다 각 좀비의 근접 전투력이 증가합니다. 좀비가 다른 유닛을 파괴하면 새 좀비 유닛이 다음 턴에 해당 타일에 생성됩니다. 좀비가 도시의 인구를 감소시키면 새 좀비 유닛이 즉시 도시 옆에 생성됩니다. 좀비는 가장 가까운 유닛, 도시 또는 방어 가능한 특수지구를 목표로 삼습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITCOMMAND_RELEASE_LEVY_DESCRIPTION" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>이 유닛의 조종을 해제합니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITCOMMAND_SPY_SUMMON_ZOMBIES_NAME" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>좀비 창궐</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITCOMMAND_SPY_SUMMON_ZOMBIES_DESCRIPTION" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>완료하면 이 도시에서 사용하는 타일마다 좀비 하나를 생성할 수 있습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_MESSAGE" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>좀비 창궐 발생시키는 데 성공</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_ENEMY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_MESSAGE" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>적으로 인해 좀비 창궐 발생</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>이 타일에 들어오는 적 유닛에게 약간의 피해를 입히고 이동력을 고갈시킵니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_TRAP" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>이 타일에 들어오는 적 유닛에게 보통 수준의 피해를 입히고 이동력을 고갈시킵니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_BARRICADE" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>이 타일과 인접 타일에 들어오는 적 유닛에게 약간의 피해를 입히고 통제 지역 영향력을 행사합니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TOWERDEFENSE_ZOMBIE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_DESC" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>돌연변이 강도 +{Property}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_SUMMARY" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>{2_CityName}에서 요원 {1_unitName}이(가) 인구를 감염시켜, 도시를 공격하는 좀비 떼를 발생시키는 데 성공했습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_ENEMY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_SUMMARY" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>{1_CityName}에서 적 스파이가 인구를 감염시켜, 현재 도시를 위협하는 좀비 떼를 발생시키는 데 성공했습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ALCAZAR_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ALCAZAR_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MAORI_PA_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MAORI_PA_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ROMAN_FORT_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ROMAN_FORT_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_FORT_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_FORT_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_VAMPIRE_CASTLE_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_VAMPIRE_CASTLE_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_GREAT_WALL_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_GREAT_WALL_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_BARRICADE}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_NAME" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>좀비</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Barykada|Barykady|Barykadzie|Barykadę|Barykadą|Barykadzie|barykada|barykady|barykadzie|barykadę|barykadą|barykadzie</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Wzmocniona barykada|Wzmocnionej barykady|Wzmocnionej barykadzie|Wzmocnioną barykadę|Wzmocnioną barykadą|Wzmocnionej barykadzie|wzmocniona barykada|wzmocnionej barykady|wzmocnionej barykadzie|wzmocnioną barykadę|wzmocnioną barykadą|wzmocnionej barykadzie</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Pułapka|Pułapki|Pułapce|Pułapkę|Pułapką|Pułapce|pułapka|pułapki|pułapce|pułapkę|pułapką|pułapce</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Zmodernizowana pułapka|Zmodernizowanej pułapki|Zmodernizowanej pułapce|Zmodernizowaną pułapkę|Zmodernizowaną pułapką|Zmodernizowanej pułapce|zmodernizowana pułapka|zmodernizowanej pułapki|zmodernizowanej pułapce|zmodernizowaną pułapkę|zmodernizowaną pułapką|zmodernizowanej pułapce</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_RELIGIOUS_NAME" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Przekabacenie nieumarłych|Przekabacenia nieumarłych|Przekabaceniu nieumarłych|Przekabacenie nieumarłych|Przekabaceniem nieumarłych|Przekabaceniu nieumarłych|przekabacenie nieumarłych|przekabacenia nieumarłych|przekabaceniu nieumarłych|przekabacenie nieumarłych|przekabaceniem nieumarłych|przekabaceniu nieumarłych</Text>
      <Gender>neuter</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_SCIENCE_NAME" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Mroczny sygnał|Mrocznego sygnału|Mrocznemu sygnałowi|Mroczny sygnał|Mrocznym sygnałem|Mrocznym sygnale|mroczny sygnał|mrocznego sygnału|mrocznemu sygnałowi|mroczny sygnał|mrocznym sygnałem|mrocznym sygnale</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_CONTENT_TITLE" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Obrona przed zombie</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_WELCOME_TITLE" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Witaj</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_WELCOME_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Tryb obrony przed zombie wprowadza do gry poważne zagrożenie dla twojej cywilizacji: zmarłych, którzy nie chcą spoczywać w pokoju. Zombie mogą powstawać wśród wojennej zawieruchy i żerując na twoich i cudzych ziemiach, rozprzestrzeniać swą zabójczą klątwę. Nie pozwól, by horda opanowała twoje miasta – chroń je przez choćby jeszcze jedną turę!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_TITLE" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Zombie</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Zombie to jednostki walczące w zwarciu, które przemierzają pustkowia. Nie mogą plądrować ulepszeń – po prostu nie są tym zainteresowane. Ale natychmiast rzucą się na każdą jednostkę wędrującą poza murami miast, więc wyruszając w drogę, miej oczy dookoła głowy. Zombie mogą też zaatakować twoje miasta, zasilając swe szeregi ich zabitymi mieszkańcami...</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_2" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Gdy na mapie ginie jednostka, istnieje niewielkie prawdopodobieństwo, że kilka tur później wróci jako zombie. Jednak gdy jednostka zginie z ręki zombie, to w następnej turze na pewno powróci jako żywy trup. Zagrożenie ze strony nieumarłych nieustannie rośnie – każde zabite na świecie zombie sprawia, że pozostali i nowi nieumarli stają się jeszcze silniejsi. Upewnij się, że wiesz, na co się piszesz, idąc na wojnę z martwymi!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_3" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Dzielnice świątynne i kampusy oferują tymczasowe rozwiązanie problemu hordy zombie – projekty „Przekabacenie nieumarłych” (dzielnica świątynna) i „Mroczny sygnał” (kampus). Pozwalają one na chwilę przejąć kontrolę nad zombie znajdującymi się w granicach twojego miasta i wykorzystać ją przeciwko twym wrogom. Pamiętaj tylko, aby zachować bezpieczną odległość od takiego nieumarłego wojska, gdy utracisz nad nim władzę... lub pozbędziesz się jej ze względów strategicznych. Ponadto twoi szpiedzy mogą rozprzestrzeniać zabójczą klątwę wśród twych wrogów za pomocą działania „Epidemia zombie”.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_TITLE" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Obrona</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Twoje ziemie nie są bezbronne w starciu z hordą. Poza projektami dostępnymi w dzielnicach świątynnych i na kampusach masz do dyspozycji również barykady i pułapki konstruowane przez budowniczych, które pomogą ci odeprzeć atak wrogów (zarówno żywych, jak i nieumarłych). Barykada zadaje niewielkie obrażenia każdej wrogiej jednostce, która przejdzie przez zajmowane przez nią pole lub pola z nią sąsiadujące, a pułapka zadaje znaczne obrażenia każdej wrogiej jednostce, która wejdzie na zajmowane przez nią pole. Późniejsze epoki pozwalają tworzyć potężniejsze barykady i pułapki.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_PARA_2" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Chociaż te instalacje obronne służą przede wszystkim walce z żywymi trupami, to sprawdzą się także w przypadku przeciwników, którzy śmierć mają jeszcze przed sobą, bo zadają obrażenia każdemu wrogowi. Stosuj je z głową, a może uda ci się przetrwać jeszcze jedną noc.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Niesamowitość zombie wynika z ich niejednoznaczności. Czy są poruszającą się materią nieożywioną? A może jakimś rodzajem żywych istot? Obrona przed atakami ludzi opiera się na kilku założeniach, które nie sprawdzają się w przypadku nieumarłych, a które dotyczą bólu, zastraszenia, wyczerpania. Drut kolczasty nie robi żadnego wrażenia na czymś, co niczego nie czuje. Dodatkowo uzbrojenie zombie jest ograniczone – nie korzystają one z trebuszy ani z płonących strzał. Dlatego broniąc się przed żywymi trupami, należy je traktować nie jako myślącego wroga, ale jako poruszającą się materię. Zaostrzone kołki służą unieruchamianiu zombie, a nie ich zabijaniu, wieże z podnoszonymi drabinami zapewniają schronienie przed wrogiem, który nie jest w stanie wspiąć się po linie, a rowy powstrzymują przeciwników, którzy nie potrafią zbudować mostu (przynajmniej do chwili, gdy pojawi się ich tak wiele, że zasypią rów swoimi ciałami).</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Żywe trupy nie męczą się. To ich największa przewaga – niczym morze nieustannie napierają na bariery wzniesione, by ich powstrzymać. W końcu pękają nie tylko ściany z drewna i bambusa, ale również mury wzniesione z polnego kamienia. I tutaj do akcji wkraczają nowoczesne materiały – żelbet i stal. Tak jak renesansowe forty w kształcie gwiazd z ich pochyłymi ścianami zostały zaprojektowane tak, by odbijać, a nie absorbować, trafienia kul armatnich, tak nowoczesne systemy obronne skupiają się na odbijaniu nieumarłych zamiast ich prostego zatrzymywania. Elastyczne materiały mogą się wygiąć, ale nie pękną, gdy żywe trupy bez przerwy na nie napierają. Gładkie powierzchnie nie dają oparcia dla kościstych palców, a śluzy umożliwiają przepłukiwanie rowów i fos, aby zapobiec zasypaniu ich stosami zwłok, na które nie były odporne starsze systemy obrony przed zombie. Korzystając z tych zdobyczy techniki, powinniśmy być bezpieczni. Raczej.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Podczas gdy mury służą do trzymania wrogów na bezpieczną odległość, przeznaczeniem pułapek jest eliminowanie, spowalnianie lub unieruchamianie przeciwników. I chociaż żywe trupy są nieugięte, to sprytem nie grzeszą. Pojedynczy człowiek w wieży ze swoim soczystym ludzkim mózgiem to nierzadko wystarczająco atrakcyjna przynęta, by zwabić nieumarłych – lub wrogo nastawionych ludzi szukających „niestrzeżonych” przeciwników – w miejsce, gdzie można sobie z nimi łatwo poradzić. Ale pozbywanie się nieumarłych jest o wiele bardziej skomplikowane niż rozprawianie się z żywymi ludźmi. Tych pierwszych nie da się przegonić ani nawet krytycznie zranić – jedynym wyjściem jest ich unicestwienie. Istnieje wiele różnych rodzajów stosownych starożytnych pułapek – od płonącej smoły, przez wilcze doły, aż po proste wieże obsadzone łucznikami (w ich przypadku skuteczność gwałtownie spada, gdy zabraknie strzał...).</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Z biegiem lat dowiedzieliśmy się więcej o nieumarłej grozie. We wcześniejszych pułapkach wykorzystywaliśmy żywych ludzi (zwykle ochotników, choć nie zawsze) w roli przynęty – obecnie dysponujemy chemicznymi i zwierzęcymi substytutami opracowanymi przez naszych inżynierów. Ponadto pociski z wgłębieniem i pociski przeciwpiechotne powodują większe uszkodzenia tkanek i zwiększają celność strzałów. Nie każdy łucznik to Wilhelm Tell, który jest w stanie trafić jabłko bełtem z kuszy, a gwintowanie luf i lunety oznaczają coraz dokładniejsze eliminowanie przeciwników. Do tego bunkry ze snajperami sprawdzają się zarówno w walce z zombie, jak i z każdym innym wrogiem. Rafinowana ropa naftowa i napalm pozwalają unicestwiać zombie – i zwykłych przeciwników – w sposób niemożliwy do uzyskania przy stosowaniu dawnych materiałów. Ponadto nowoczesne pułapki wykorzystują słabości zombie: horda nieumarłych maszerująca bez końca w kółko i ścigająca mózg na mechanicznym wysięgniku (jak psy uganiające się za sztucznym zającem na torze wyścigowym) to o wiele wydajniejsze rozwiązanie niż jakiś wykopany w ziemi dół.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Zombie stały się jednym z najbardziej rozpoznawalnych motywów filmów i literatury grozy. Mimo to wizja wygłodniałych, poruszających się chwiejnym krokiem zwłok, a zwłaszcza pomysł globalnej pandemii zmieniającej ludzi w nieumarłych, to coś, co pojawiło się dopiero niedawno. W wielu karaibskich ludowych tradycjach zombi lub jumbee to ogólne określenie złowrogiego ducha, oparte na przekazach wywodzących się z tradycji Afryki Zachodniej. Ale na Haiti zombie stały się czymś innym – symbolem wszystkich okropności niewolnictwa. Dla zniewolonych Afrykanów w ówczesnej francuskiej kolonii Saint-Domingue życie było prawie nie do zniesienia. Śmierć obiecywała wyzwolenie i powrót – według tradycji – do raju w Afryce, w którym wreszcie mogliby być wolni. Ale samobójstwo zamykało te drzwi i sprawiało, że nieszczęsny duch pozostawał na zawsze na Karaibach, w wiecznej niewoli jako zombie.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>W następstwie rewolucji haitańskiej zombie wszedł do lokalnego folkloru jako sługa złowrogiego czarownika lub, według niektórych przekazów, kapłan voudun (voodoo). Zombie – będący w transie ludzie lub ożywione zwłoki – nadal pracowały dla swojego pana, przypominając w ten sposób o przerażającym powrocie niewolnictwa ludowi, który ciężko walczył, aby stać się wolnym i wolnym pozostać. Właśnie w tej postaci zombie pojawiły się po raz pierwszy w globalnej popkulturze. Amerykańskie filmy wykorzystywały je jako symbol egzotycznej magii w rasistowskich często przedstawieniach Karaibów lub po prostu „innych” religii. Gdzie indziej zombie pojawiły się jako symbol obawy przed kradzieżą czyjejś pracy, czy to przez powrót jawnego niewolnictwa, czy też jako metafora zagmatwanego i opartego na wyzysku sposobu, w jaki nowe formy kapitalizmu przejawiały się na obszarach takich jak RPA.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Jednak większość ludzi zna hordy rozsławione przez George'a Romero w jego filmie „Noc żywych trupów”. Reżyser przedstawia świat wywrócony do góry nogami, w którym niepogrzebani zmarli wracają do życia. Warto zauważyć, że Romero nigdy nie używa terminu „zombie”, zamiast tego mówiąc o „ghulach”, co samo w sobie jest odniesieniem do arabskiego ducha-kanibala. Zombie pod koniec XX w. stały się nową metaforą, w której nieumarli są manifestacją bezmyślnego, bezdusznego konsumpcjonizmu, obawy przed radioaktywnym opadem lub groźby wystąpienia masowych niepokojów społecznych. W XXI w. stały się ściśle związane ze strachem przed chorobami i upadkiem społeczeństwa. Literatura i filmy grozy przeniosły nacisk ze strachu przed utratą panowania nad sobą na fantazję o przetrwaniu w świecie, w którym wszystko inne umarło. Zombie są w tym ujęciu niszczycielską siłą, którą można – jeśli się uda – wykorzystać do własnych celów.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Nienadające się do eksploatacji ulepszenie wczesnego etapu rozgrywki zadające niewielkie obrażenia wrogim jednostkom, które przechodzą przez zajmowane przez nie lub sąsiednie pole, oraz obejmujące te jednostki strefą kontroli. Odblokowywane przy opracowaniu technologii inżynierii wojskowej i wznoszone z wykorzystaniem punktu potencjału budowniczego. Nie blokuje ruchu jednostek przez pole, na którym się znajduje.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Nienadające się do eksploatacji ulepszenie późnego etapu rozgrywki zadające średnie obrażenia wrogim jednostkom, które przechodzą przez zajmowane przez nie lub sąsiednie pole, oraz obejmujące je strefą kontroli. Odblokowywane przy opracowaniu technologii gwintowania i wznoszone z wykorzystaniem punktu potencjału inżyniera wojskowego. Nie blokuje ruchu jednostek przez pole, na którym się znajduje.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Nienadające się do eksploatacji ulepszenie wczesnego etapu rozgrywki zadające średnie obrażenia wrogim jednostkom, które przechodzą przez zajmowane przez nie pole, oraz odbierające im punkty ruchu. Odblokowywane przy opracowaniu technologii budownictwa i wznoszone z wykorzystaniem punktu potencjału budowniczego. Nie blokuje ruchu jednostek przez pole, na którym się znajduje.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Nienadające się do eksploatacji ulepszenie późnego etapu rozgrywki zadające znaczne obrażenia wrogim jednostkom, które przechodzą przez zajmowane przez nie pole, oraz odbierające im punkty ruchu. Odblokowywane przy opracowaniu technologii balistyki i wznoszone z wykorzystaniem punktu potencjału inżyniera wojskowego. Nie blokuje ruchu jednostek przez pole, na którym się znajduje.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_RELIGIOUS_DESCRIPTION" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Po ukończeniu daje kontrolę nad zombie znajdującymi się w danej chwili na terytorium tego miasta. Kontrola trwa 15 tur.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_SCIENCE_DESCRIPTION" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Po ukończeniu daje kontrolę nad zombie znajdującymi się w danej chwili na terytorium tego miasta. Kontrola trwa 30 tur.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_DESCRIPTION" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Wroga jednostka walcząca w zwarciu, która może pojawić się na mapie w miejscu śmieci innej jednostki. Jej siła bojowa wzrasta z każdą wyeliminowaną w skali globalnej jednostką zombie. Jeśli zombie zniszczy inną jednostkę, to w następnej turze na jej miejscu pojawi się nowe zombie. Jeśli zombie zmniejszą populację miasta, to w jego sąsiedztwie natychmiast pojawia się ich nowa jednostka. Zombie atakują najbliżej położoną jednostkę, miasto lub dzielnicę zdolną do obrony.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITCOMMAND_RELEASE_LEVY_DESCRIPTION" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Zwolnij tę jednostkę.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITCOMMAND_SPY_SUMMON_ZOMBIES_NAME" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Epidemia zombie</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITCOMMAND_SPY_SUMMON_ZOMBIES_DESCRIPTION" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Po ukończeniu zapewnia szansę na przyzwanie po jednym zombie na każde pole wykorzystywane przez to miasto.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_MESSAGE" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Udało się doprowadzić do wybuchu epidemii zombie</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_ENEMY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_MESSAGE" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Wróg doprowadził do wybuchu epidemii zombie</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Zadaje niewielkie obrażenia wrogim jednostkom, które przechodzą przez zajmowane przez nią pole, oraz odbiera im punkty ruchu.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_TRAP" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Zadaje średnie obrażenia wrogim jednostkom, które przechodzą przez zajmowane przez nią pole, oraz odbiera im punkty ruchu.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_BARRICADE" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Zadaje niewielkie obrażenia wrogim jednostkom, które przechodzą przez zajmowane przez nią lub sąsiednie pole, oraz obejmuje te jednostki strefą kontroli.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TOWERDEFENSE_ZOMBIE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_DESC" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>+{Property} do siły mutacji</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_SUMMARY" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Twój agent {1_unitName} w {2_CityName[6]} zdołał zainfekować tamtejszą populację. Powstała w ten sposób horda zombie atakuje miasto.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_ENEMY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_SUMMARY" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Szpieg wroga zainfekował mieszkańców {1_CityName[2]}, tworząc hordę zombie, która zagraża teraz twojemu miastu.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ALCAZAR_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ALCAZAR_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MAORI_PA_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MAORI_PA_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ROMAN_FORT_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ROMAN_FORT_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_FORT_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_FORT_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_VAMPIRE_CASTLE_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_VAMPIRE_CASTLE_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_GREAT_WALL_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_GREAT_WALL_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_BARRICADE}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_NAME" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Zombie</Text>
      <Gender>neuter</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Баррикада|баррикады|баррикаде|баррикаду|баррикадой|баррикаде</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Укрепленная баррикада|укрепленной баррикады|укрепленной баррикаде|укрепленную баррикаду|укрепленной баррикадой|укрепленной баррикаде</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Ловушка|ловушки|ловушке|ловушку|ловушкой|ловушке</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Улучшенная ловушка|улучшенной ловушки|улучшенной ловушке|улучшенную ловушку|улучшенной ловушкой|улучшенной ловушке</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_RELIGIOUS_NAME" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Подчинение нежити|подчинения нежити|подчинению нежити|подчинение нежити|подчинением нежити|подчинении нежити</Text>
      <Gender>neuter</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_SCIENCE_NAME" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Темный сигнал|темного сигнала|темному сигналу|темный сигнал|темным сигналом|темном сигнале</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_CONTENT_TITLE" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Оборона от зомби</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_WELCOME_TITLE" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Добро пожаловать</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_WELCOME_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Режим обороны от зомби добавляет в игру новую серьезную угрозу для вашей цивилизации — мертвецов, не желающих покоиться в земле. Зомби появляются на местах битв и разносят свою смертельную заразу. Не дайте им захлестнуть ваши города и держитесь — хотя бы еще один ход!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_TITLE" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Зомби</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Зомби — это юниты ближнего боя, которые бесцельно бродят по пустошам. Они не разграбляют ваши улучшения, им это просто не интересно. Но они без промедления бросятся на любой юнит, вышедший на открытую местность, поэтому, покидая город, смотрите по сторонам. Также они нападают на города и превращают погибшее население в новых зомби.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_2" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Когда на карте погибает юнит, он с небольшой вероятностью может спустя несколько ходов возродиться в виде зомби. Однако если юнит погибает от рук зомби, он совершенно точно возродится в следующий ход. Со временем ходячие мертвецы начинают представлять всё большую опасность: чем больше зомби убивают игроки, тем сильнее становятся оставшиеся и новые зомби. Если решили пойти войной на мертвецов, учитывайте последствия!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_3" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Временное решение проблемы зомби предлагают священные места и кампусы. Проект «Оживление мертвых» в священном месте и проект «Темный сигнал» в кампусе позволяют временно брать под контроль зомби, находящихся в границах вашего города, и направлять их на врагов. Главное — постарайтесь убраться подальше прежде, чем контроль иссякнет... или вы прервете его в подходящий момент. Кроме того, шпионы могут распространять смертельную заразу среди врагов при помощи действия «Нашествие зомби».</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_TITLE" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Оборона</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Ваши земли не беззащитны перед ордами зомби. Помимо проектов в священных местах и кампусах, ваши строители могут строить баррикады и ловушки для врагов — как живых, так и мертвых. Баррикада наносит небольшой урон любому вражескому юниту, проходящему по ней или по соседней с ней клетке, а ловушка наносит серьезный урон каждому вражескому юниту, зашедшему на ее клетку. В более поздних эпохах у вас появится возможность строить более мощные баррикады и ловушки.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_PARA_2" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Эти сооружения защищают не только от ходячих мертвецов, но и от живых противников — им все равно, кому наносить урон. Расставьте их с умом, и у вас появится шанс дожить до рассвета.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Зомби страшны тем, что природа их неясна. Что они такое: просто ходячие трупы или все-таки живые существа? Меры обороны от людей призваны причинять врагам боль, вызывать у них страх и усталость — но к ходячим мертвецам всё это неприменимо. Какой толк от колючей проволоки, если противник ничего не чувствует? К тому же арсенал зомби очень ограничен: они не строят требушеты и не стреляют из луков. Поэтому сооружения для защиты от мертвецов строятся исходя их того, что противник — просто ходячая плоть. Заостренные колья не убивают, а лишь останавливают зомби. Башни с подъемными лестницами спасают от врагов, которым не хватает ума забраться вверх по веревке, а рвы представляют непреодолимую преграду для тех, кто не может навести через них мост. Всё это работает — по крайней мере до тех пор, пока мертвецов не станет слишком много.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Ходячие мертвецы не устают. В этом их главная сила. Словно морские волны, они неустанно бьются о возведенные для защиты от них сооружения. Со временем они способны сломать и дерево, и бамбук, и даже каменные стены. И тогда надо будет обратить внимание на современные материалы — железобетон и сталь. Стены бастионов эпохи Возрождения строились с наклоном, чтобы отражать снаряды артиллерии, а не поглощать их удары. Точно так же современные оборонительные сооружения строятся таким образом, чтобы отражать атаки живых мертвецов, а не просто их останавливать. Под напором зомби гибкие материалы гнутся, но не ломаются. За гладкие поверхности трудно зацепиться пальцами, а специально оборудованные шлюзы позволяют смывать кучи тел, которыми мертвецы засыпают рвы. С такими высокотехнологичными средствами защиты нам ничего не грозит. Будем надеяться.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Стены строят для того, чтобы перекрыть противнику дорогу, а ловушки — чтобы его уничтожить, замедлить или обездвижить. Ходячие мертвецы не знают усталости, но и ума у них тоже немного. Посадите в башню одного-единственного добровольца, и на запах его сочного мозга со всей округи сбегутся голодные мертвецы — или живые враги, позарившиеся на возможность уничтожить «незащищенную цель». Тут-то их и можно будет истребить. Впрочем, победить нежить в каком-то смысле сложнее, чем живых противников. Их нельзя прогнать или вывести из строя — их можно только уничтожить. Древние ловушки представляли собой горящий деготь, потайные ямы и просто башни со стрелками. Лишь бы хватило стрел…</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>За годы и столетия мы тщательно изучили живых мертвецов. Раньше мы заманивали их в ловушки на живца (роль которых выполняли добровольцы — и не только), но теперь наши ученые разработали химические и животные аналоги. Кроме того, современные экспансивные пули имеют высокую точность и наносят мертвецам больший урон. Не каждый лучник — Вильгельм Телль, способный попасть в яблочко из арбалета. Но нарезные стволы и оптические прицелы позволяют стрелять всё точнее, а бункеры со снайперами так же эффективны против нежити, как и против живого противника. Очищенные нефтепродукты и напалм тоже уничтожают зомби — да и живых людей — куда эффективнее своих древних аналогов. К тому же современные ловушки учитывают слабые места зомби. Заставить орду живых мертвецов бегать по кругу за мозгами на моторизованной тележке, словно борзых на собачьих бегах, куда эффективнее, чем просто заманить их в яму.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Зомби стали одним из самых узнаваемых клише в жанре ужасов. Однако образы шаркающих ногами ненасытных мертвецов и, в особенности, всемирного нашествия нежити сформировались только в последние годы. Во многих карибских фольклорных традициях зомби или джамби — общее название для злых духов, происходящее из фольклора Западной Африки. Но на Гаити зомби считались чем-то иным — воплощением всех ужасов рабства. Жизнь африканских рабов во французской колонии Сан-Доминго, как раньше называли Гаити, была невыносимой. Согласно традиционным верованиям, смерть сулила освобождение и возвращение в рай в Африке, где рабы наконец могли обрести свободу. Однако самоубийцам путь к освобождению был закрыт. Их несчастным духам было суждено навсегда остаться на Карибах в качестве рабов — зомби.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>После Гаитянской революции зомби вошли в местный фольклор как слуги злых колдунов или, в некоторых рассказах, жрецов вуду. Заколдованные или оживленные зомби продолжали трудиться на своего хозяина, тем самым напоминая о пугающем возврате к рабству народу, который яростно сражался за свою свободу. Именно в этом смысле зомби впервые вошли в мировую популярную культуру. В американских фильмах зомби служили символом экзотической магии при изображении карибских или просто «чужих» верований, которое зачастую грешило расизмом. В других странах зомби воплощали страх украденного труда, будь то возвращение к рабству или новые и непонятные формы капиталистической эксплуатации в таких регионах, как Южная Африка.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Но большинству людей полчища зомби, вероятно, знакомы по прославившему их фильму Джорджа Ромеро «Ночь живых мертвецов». В нем Ромеро представляет зрителю перевернутый вверх тормашками мир, где непогребенные мертвецы оживают. Примечательно, что в англоязычном оригинале фильма Ромеро ни разу не использует термин «зомби», а называет своих персонажей «гулями». Гуль — дух-людоед в арабской мифологии. К концу XX века зомби как метафора получили новое наполнение: олицетворение безмозглого, бездушного потребительства, боязнь ядерной катастрофы, угроза колоссальных социальных потрясений. В XXI веке образ зомби тесно связан со страхом эпидемий и распадом общества. Фокус в жанре ужасов сместился со страха потерять контроль над собой на фантазии о выживании в мире, где все остальные мертвы. Здесь зомби являются сугубо разрушительной силой — силой, которой можно воспользоваться.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Необрабатываемое улучшение ранних эпох. Создает зону контроля и наносит небольшой урон вражеским юнитам, проходящим по этой или соседним клеткам. Доступно после открытия военной инженерии, возводится строителем. Не блокирует перемещение через клетку.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Необрабатываемое улучшение поздних эпох. Создает зону контроля и наносит средний урон вражеским юнитам, проходящим по этой или соседним клеткам. Доступно после открытия нарезных стволов, возводится военным инженером. Не блокирует перемещение через клетку.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Необрабатываемое улучшение ранних эпох. Наносит средний урон проходящим по этой клетке вражеским юнитам и обнуляет их очки перемещения. Доступно после открытия строительства, возводится строителем. Не блокирует перемещение через клетку.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Необрабатываемое улучшение поздних эпох. Наносит значительный урон проходящим по этой клетке вражеским юнитам и обнуляет их очки перемещения. Доступно после открытия баллистики, возводится военным инженером. Не блокирует перемещение через клетку.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_RELIGIOUS_DESCRIPTION" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>По завершении вы получите контроль над зомби на территории этого города.  Контроль действует 15 ходов.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_SCIENCE_DESCRIPTION" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>По завершении вы получите контроль над зомби на территории этого города.  Контроль действует 30 ходов.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_DESCRIPTION" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Враждебный юнит ближнего боя, который может появиться на карте в месте гибели другого юнита. Мощь зомби в ближнем бою возрастает с каждым зомби, убитым в мире. Если от рук зомби погибает другой юнит, на следующем ходу на клетке этого юнита появляется новый юнит зомби. Если зомби сокращает население города, рядом с этим городом появляется новый юнит зомби. Зомби нападают на ближайшие юниты, города и защищенные районы.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITCOMMAND_RELEASE_LEVY_DESCRIPTION" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Прервать контроль над этим юнитом.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITCOMMAND_SPY_SUMMON_ZOMBIES_NAME" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Вызвать нашествие зомби</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITCOMMAND_SPY_SUMMON_ZOMBIES_DESCRIPTION" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>По завершении с некоторым шансом создает зомби на каждой обрабатываемой клетке города.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_MESSAGE" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Успешно вызвано нашествие зомби</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_ENEMY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_MESSAGE" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Враг вызвал нашествие зомби.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Наносит небольшой урон проходящим по этой клетке вражеским юнитам, обнуляет их очки перемещения.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_TRAP" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Наносит средний урон проходящим по этой клетке вражеским юнитам, обнуляет их очки перемещения.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_BARRICADE" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Наносит небольшой урон враждебным юнитам, проходящим по ее или соседним с ней клеткам, а также имеет зону контроля.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TOWERDEFENSE_ZOMBIE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_DESC" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>+{Property} от мутаций</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_SUMMARY" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Ваш агент {1_unitName} {1_unitName : gender feminine?заразила; masculine?заразил; other?заразил;} население {2_CityName[2]}, и теперь городу угрожает нападение орды зомби.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_ENEMY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_SUMMARY" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Вражескому шпиону удалось заразить население города {1_CityName}, и теперь вам угрожает орда зомби.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ALCAZAR_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ALCAZAR_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MAORI_PA_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MAORI_PA_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ROMAN_FORT_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ROMAN_FORT_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_FORT_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_FORT_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_VAMPIRE_CASTLE_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_VAMPIRE_CASTLE_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_GREAT_WALL_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_GREAT_WALL_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_BARRICADE}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_NAME" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Зомби|зомби|зомби|зомби|зомби|зомби</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>路障</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>强化路障</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>陷阱</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>现代陷阱</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_RELIGIOUS_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>亡灵掌控</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_SCIENCE_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>黑暗信号</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_CONTENT_TITLE" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>丧尸之围</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_WELCOME_TITLE" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>欢迎</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_WELCOME_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>“丧尸之围”模式为您的文明带来了一个重大威胁：不安分的活死人。丧尸会从战场的灰烬中爬起，在各个文明的土地上肆虐，不断传播死亡诅咒。尝试阻止他们攻破你的城市，至少也要再坚持一回合！</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_TITLE" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>丧尸</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>丧尸是在废墟中游荡的近战单位。他们无法掠夺改良设施，也对这类东西也不感兴趣。但如果发现单位，他们便会立刻恶狠狠地扑上去。所以离开城市时请务必当心。他们也能对城市发起攻击，并使被杀死的人口变成丧尸…</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_2" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>单位在地图上死去后，便有较小概率在数回合后变为丧尸。而如果一个单位遭到丧尸攻击而死亡，下回合便会变为丧尸。来自不死者的威胁将逐步提升——世界上每有一个丧尸遭到击杀，剩余和新变出的丧尸就会变强。因此在向活死人发起进攻之前，务必想好万全之策！</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_3" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>面对成群的丧尸，圣地和学院能提供临时解决方案。利用圣地中的“亡灵掌控”或学院中的“黑暗信号”项目可以短时间控制城市领土中的丧尸，这意味着可以利用丧尸群来对付敌人。但要注意控制失效的期限，或者策略性地在适当的时间点选择结束控制。此外，您的间谍也可以借助“丧尸爆发”操作为敌人带来死亡诅咒。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_TITLE" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>防御</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>面对成群的敌人，您的土地并非全无防备。除圣地和学院中的项目外，您的建造者还可以建造路障或陷阱来抵御敌人（无论他们是死是活）。路障会对从其上方或相邻单元格经过的任何敌方单位造成少量伤害，而陷阱则会对直接经过其上方的任何敌方单位造成大量伤害。随着时代发展，玩家将能建造更强大的路障和陷阱。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_PARA_2" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>这些建筑对活死人有极强的防御效果，但也同样适用于对付其他敌人，因为它们能够对任何敌人输出伤害。如明智地进行部署，它们将有效保护您的文明。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>丧尸的恐怖感源于它们的不确定性。它们仅仅是一堆能动的腐肉，还是某种生物？疼痛、恐吓、疲惫等对人类有效的防御手段对活死人完全无效。带刺的铁丝网在毫无痛觉的丧尸面前没有任何意义。另外，丧尸的攻击手段也十分有限，它们不会建造投石机，也不会发射弓箭。因此针对它们进行防御时不应将其视为有思想的敌人，而应当看作会移动的物体。锋利的尖刺不是为了造成击杀，而是要使其无法动弹；装有伸缩梯子的塔楼可以防止它们沿绳索攀爬而上；壕沟也可以阻挡无法建造桥梁的它们。当然，如果它们数量过多，那就另当别论了。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>活死人永远不会感到疲倦，但这也是其优势所在。它们就像海水一样，不断冲击着防御工事。最终，由木头和竹刺搭建、甚至由石头堆砌的防御墙也会土崩瓦解。因此，钢筋混凝土、钢铁等现代材料便开始大行其道。例如文艺复兴时期的星形要塞，其墙壁拥有一定倾角，设计理念是弹开炮火，而非直接硬扛其攻击。现代防御着重于用以柔克刚的方式来对付活死人，而不只是简单地阻挡它们的前进脚步。在丧尸的不断推动下，柔性材料会弯曲，但不会断裂。光滑的表面让这些瘦骨嶙峋的手指无处着力，而水闸则能对沟渠和壕沟进行水流冲刷，以防止尸体堆积成山而导致老式丧尸防御设施失效。我们应该能安全地躲在这些防御工事后面。至少理论来说是这样。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>高墙是尝试把敌人阻挡在外的防御手段，而陷阱的作用却是为了消灭敌人、延缓其行进速度，或使其无法动弹。虽然丧尸冷酷无情，但也毫无智商。而一座塔楼里的一个大活人，凭借美味而聪明的脑袋瓜，就可以充当极好的诱饵，把丧尸或敌人勾引过来，使其进入埋伏圈。但和丧尸作战有所不同。它们不能被赶走，甚至不会受到致命伤，唯一有效手段就是将其消灭。古代陷阱拥有燃烧的沥青、隐藏的坑洞，或是挤满弓箭手的塔楼。至少，可以撑到箭射完为止…</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>随着岁月的流逝，我们对不死者的威胁有了更深入的了解。早期的陷阱利用大活人作为诱饵（无论其是否出于自愿）。而现在，工程师们已经研发出了化学或动物替代品。此外，空尖弹或达姆弹提升了对身体组织的伤害，并增加了准确性。并不是每个弓箭手都像威廉·退尔那般精准，能用弓箭百步穿杨穿透苹果；但步枪和瞄准镜大幅提升了杀戮的精确度，在掩体中进行射击的狙击手对丧尸的杀伤力丝毫不亚于对普通敌人的效果。精炼石油和凝固汽油弹则拥有早期防御手段无法达到的效果，可以将丧尸或普通人类敌人烧成灰烬。此外，现代陷阱也充分利用了丧尸的弱点，能让一大群活死人像赛狗一样永无休止地在机械轨道上绕圈追逐新鲜人脑。这样的效果无疑比简单挖个坑要好上许多。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>丧尸已然成为最具代表性的恐怖代名词之一。但眼红贪婪、步履蹒跚的活死人形象，尤其是丧尸病全球大流行的概念却是近年才出现的。在许多加勒比民俗传统中，丧尸或恶魔普遍代表邪恶的灵魂，来源于西非传统。但在海地，丧尸则另有所指，其代表着奴隶制带来的恐怖。对当时法国殖民地圣多明戈的非洲奴隶来说，生活可以说是难以忍受的痛苦。而死亡则是一种解脱，可以让他们回到非洲传说中的天堂，并在那里重获自由。但如果选择自杀，通往天堂的大门将永远关闭，这些不幸的灵魂也将困在加勒比海永世为奴——也就是变为丧尸。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>海地革命之后，当地民间传说中将丧尸描述为恶毒巫师的仆人，另一些传说则将其解释为巫毒教祭司。无论异变原因是丧失心智还是死而复生，丧尸都将继续为主人效劳，这也不断警醒着这个历尽千辛万苦才获得独立的民族，过去的奴役历史有多么恐怖。实际上正是从这个意义上来讲，丧尸才首次出现在全球流行文化中。美国电影将丧尸用作异域魔法的象征，通常是对加勒比或信仰其他宗教地区带有歧视色彩的描绘。在其他地方，丧尸的出现则是表达了对劳动力剥削的恐惧，其中既有奴隶制的回归，也隐喻了新式资本主义在南非等地区令人愤懑的剥削方式。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>大多数人对丧尸的了解可能都源于著名恐怖片导演乔治·罗梅罗和他的电影《活死人之夜》。在本片中，罗梅罗呈现了一个颠覆三观的世界，未埋葬的死者再度复活。值得注意的是，罗梅罗从未使用“丧尸”一词，而是称其为“食尸鬼”，这指的是一种阿拉伯食人恶魔。在20世纪晚期，丧尸成为了一个新的隐喻，代表没有思想没有灵魂的消费主义、对核辐射的恐惧、或是大规模社会动荡带来的威胁。在21世纪，丧尸则与疾病恐惧和社会崩溃密切相关。恐怖的根源已经由对一个人失控的恐惧转变为在万物崩坏之后继续求生的幻想。这里所指的丧尸是一种终极的破坏力，而也许，这种破坏力也可以转变为你的优势。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>游戏早期的改良设施，公民无法在此工作，对经过其上方或相邻单元格的敌方单位造成少量伤害，并形成控制区。随“军事工程学”科技解锁，使用1点建造者次数进行建造。无法阻止单位移动通过此空间。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>游戏后期的改良设施，公民无法在此工作，对经过其上方或相邻单元格的敌方单位造成中等伤害，并形成控制区。随“膛线”科技解锁，使用1点军事工程师次数进行建造。无法阻止单位移动通过此空间。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>游戏早期的改良设施，公民无法在此工作，对直接经过其上方的敌方单位造成中等伤害，并耗尽其移动力。随“建设”科技解锁，使用1点建造者次数进行建造。无法阻止单位移动通过此空间。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>游戏后期的改良设施，公民无法在此工作，对直接经过其上方的敌方单位造成大量伤害，并耗尽其移动力。随“弹道学”科技解锁，使用1点军事工程师次数进行建造。无法阻止单位移动通过此空间。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_RELIGIOUS_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>完成之后，可以控制当前处于此城领土中的丧尸。控制将持续15个回合。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_SCIENCE_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>完成之后，可以控制当前处于此城领土中的丧尸。控制将持续30个回合。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>敌对近战单位，有机率出现在地图上单位死亡之处。游戏中每有一只丧尸被消灭，所有丧尸的近战攻击力都将提升。如果丧尸杀死单位，次回合被杀单位所在单元格中将出现一只新的丧尸。如果丧尸使城市人口减少，城市旁将立即生成1个新的丧尸单位。丧尸会以最近的单位、城市或防御性区域作为攻击目标。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITCOMMAND_RELEASE_LEVY_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>放弃控制此单位。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITCOMMAND_SPY_SUMMON_ZOMBIES_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>丧尸爆发</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITCOMMAND_SPY_SUMMON_ZOMBIES_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>完成后，有一定机率根据此城改良的单元格数量来生成丧尸。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_MESSAGE" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>已成功引起丧尸爆发</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_ENEMY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_MESSAGE" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>敌人已引起丧尸爆发</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>对踏上此单元格的敌对单位造成少量伤害，并剥夺其移动力。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_TRAP" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>对踏上此单元格的敌对单位造成中等伤害，并剥夺其移动力。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_BARRICADE" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>对踏上此单元格和周边单元格的敌对单位造成少量伤害，并形成控制区。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TOWERDEFENSE_ZOMBIE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_DESC" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>+{Property}变异之力</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_SUMMARY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>您的间谍{1_unitName}在{2_CityName}成功感染了人口，丧尸群出现，并对城市发起攻击。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_ENEMY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_SUMMARY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>潜伏在{1_CityName}的敌方间谍成功感染了您的人口，丧尸群出现，对您的城市构成了威胁。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ALCAZAR_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ALCAZAR_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MAORI_PA_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MAORI_PA_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ROMAN_FORT_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ROMAN_FORT_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_FORT_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_FORT_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_VAMPIRE_CASTLE_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_VAMPIRE_CASTLE_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_GREAT_WALL_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_GREAT_WALL_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_BARRICADE}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>丧尸</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Barricada|Barricadas</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1|2</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Barricada reforzada|Barricadas reforzadas</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1|2</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Trampa|Trampas</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1|2</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Trampa modernizada|Trampas modernizadas</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1|2</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_RELIGIOUS_NAME" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Expulsar muertos vivientes|Expulsar muertos vivientes</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_SCIENCE_NAME" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Señal oscura</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_CONTENT_TITLE" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Defensa zombi</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_WELCOME_TITLE" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Bienvenida</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_WELCOME_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>El modo de juego Defensa zombi introduce una amenaza peligrosa contra tu civilización: los muertos que no se saben estar quietos. Pueden surgir zombis de las cenizas de la guerra; y, mientras atacan tus tierras y las de otros, extienden su mortal maldición. ¡Intenta impedir que abrumen tus ciudades, al menos un turno más!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_TITLE" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Zombis</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Los Zombis son unidades de cuerpo a cuerpo que vagan por los yermos. No pueden saquear mejoras; eso no les interesa. Pero irán de inmediato a por cualquier unidad que merodee por el exterior, así que no dejes de echar un ojo a las unidades que salgan de tus ciudades. También pueden atacar tus ciudades y convertir a la población en más zombis...</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_2" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Cuando una unidad muere en el mapa, tiene una pequeña probabilidad de regresar como unidad Zombi unos turnos más tarde. No obstante, si un Zombi destruye una unidad, esta se levantará seguro el turno siguiente. Aunque la amenaza de los muertos vivientes no para de crecer: por cada Zombi que caiga en cualquier lugar del mundo, los Zombis restantes y los nuevos se harán cada vez más fuertes. Asegúrate de saber dónde te metes cuando vayas a la guerra contra los muertos.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_3" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Los Lugares sagrados y los Campus tienen una solución temporal contra la horda zombi. Usar el proyecto Expulsar muertos vivientes en un Lugar sagrado o el proyecto Señal oscura en un Campus te permitirá controlar durante un rato a los Zombis que estén en los límites de tu ciudad, lo cual supone que puedes volverlos contra el enemigo. Pero asegúrate de estar fuera de su alcance cuando este control se acabe... o decidas ponerle fin por cuestiones estratégicas. Además, tus Espías pueden propagar esta mortal maldición entre el enemigo con la acción Brote zombi.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_TITLE" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Defensa</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Tus tierras no carecen de defensas contra la horda. Además de los proyectos en Lugares sagrados y Campus, los Constructores pueden crear Barricadas o Trampas para ayudar a defenderte de los enemigos (vivos o muertos). Una Barricada inflige una pequeña cantidad de daño a cualquier unidad hostil que atraviese esta o las casillas adyacentes; mientras que una Trampa inflige una cantidad de daño importante a cualquier unidad hostil que la atraviese directamente. Las épocas posteriores dan la capacidad de crear Barricadas y Trampas más efectivas.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_PARA_2" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Aunque ambas representan unas defensas poderosas contra los muertos vivientes, también pueden resultar útiles contra enemigos más vivaces, ya que infligen daño contra cualquier oponente. Planifícalas con estrategia, y puede que sobrevivas a la noche.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Lo asombroso de los zombis se debe a su ambigüedad. ¿Son solo materia inanimada o alguna clase de seres vivos? Las defensas contra las personas se basan en varias cosas que, muchas veces, no son válidas para unos cadáveres ambulantes: dolor, intimidación, desgaste. El alambre de espino no supone nada para quien no siente el dolor. Además, el armamento zombi es muy limitado: ni construyen trabuquetes ni disparan flechas. Así que las defensas contra muertos consideran a estos no un enemigo pensante, sino materia en movimiento: con las estacas no se pretende matar, sino inmovilizar; las torres con escalerillas retráctiles dan refugio contra los enemigos que no tienen cerebro para subir por una cuerda, las zanjas contienen a quienes son incapaces de tender un puente. Al menos, mientras no sean demasiados.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Los muertos vivientes no se cansan. Es su principal ventaja: como un mar, rompen sin cesar contra las defensas erigidas para detenerlos. Tarde o temprano, los muros de madera y bambú se astillan e incluso las murallas de piedra se derrumban. Aquí entran en juego los materiales modernos (hormigón armado, acero). Así como el fuerte con forma de estrella del Renacimiento, con sus muros en ángulo, se diseñó para desviar el fuego de cañón y no absorber su impacto, las defensas modernas se centran en desviar a los muertos vivientes, en lugar de simplemente detenerlos. Los materiales flexibles se doblan pero no se rompen mientras los muertos los presionan sin descanso. Las superficies lisas no proporcionan ningún asidero a los dedos huesudos, y las compuertas permiten que las zanjas y fosos se vacíen, lo que evita que se formen rampas con los cadáveres apilados que podrían superar las formas más antiguas de defensa antizombi. Deberíamos de estar seguros detrás de ellas. Deberíamos.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Mientras las murallas son un tipo de defensas que tratan de impedir que el enemigo entre, las trampas buscan eliminarlo, frenarlo o inmovilizarlo. Y, aunque los muertos vivientes son incansables, no son inteligentes. Un solo humano en una torre, con su jugoso cerebro, puede ser cebo suficiente para atraer a los zombis –o a humanos hostiles que buscan acabar con un enemigo "desprotegido"– a distancias cortas, donde acabar con ellos. Pero deshacerse de los muertos cuesta mucho más que vérselas con enemigos humanos. No se les puede rechazar ni herir de gravedad: hay que destruirlos. Las trampas antiguas pueden incluir alquitrán hirviendo, hoyos ocultos o, simplemente, torres de arqueros. Hasta que se acaban las flechas, claro...</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Con los años, hemos aprendido más sobre la amenaza de los muertos vivientes. Las primeras trampas implicaban el uso de seres humanos vivos (voluntarios o no) como cebo, pero los ingenieros han desarrollado sustitutos químicos o animales. Además, las balas de punta hueca o antipersonal hacen un daño mayor en los tejidos y tienen mayor precisión. No todos los arqueros son Guillermo Tell, capaces de atinar en una manzana con un virote de ballesta, y el estriado y las miras consiguen "muertes" cada vez más precisas. Además, los búnkeres con francotiradores funcionan tan bien contra muertos como contra otros enemigos. El petróleo refinado y el napalm permiten que se desintegren los zombis (o los enemigos humanos) de una manera impensable para los materiales anteriores. Además, las trampas modernas juegan con las debilidades de los zombis: tener a una horda de muertos vivientes marchando sin cesar en círculo, persiguiendo un cerebro en una pista mecánica como la de un canódromo, puede ser mucho más efectivo que una simple hoya.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Los zombis se han convertido en uno de los tropos de terror más reconocibles. Pero la imagen de cadáveres hambrientos y arrastrándose y, sobre todo, la idea de una pandemia global de muertos vivientes es algo que solo ha surgido en los últimos tiempos. En muchas tradiciones folclóricas caribeñas, un zombi o "jumbee" es una categoría general para un espíritu malévolo, que a su vez deriva de las tradiciones del África occidental. Pero en Haití, el zombi se convirtió en otra cosa: un remedo de todos los horrores de la esclavitud. Para los africanos esclavizados en la colonia francesa de Saint-Domingue, la vida era casi insoportable. La muerte, al menos, les prometía una liberación y un regreso a un paraíso en África donde por fin podrían ser libres, según decía la tradición. Pero el suicidio les cerraba esta puerta y hacía que el desafortunado espíritu permaneciera para siempre en el Caribe, esclavizado eternamente: un zombi.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>A raíz de la revolución haitiana, el zombi entró en el folclore local como sirviente de un hechicero malévolo o, según algunos relatos, de un sacerdote de voudun (vudú). El zombi, en trance o reanimado, continuaba trabajando para su amo, recordando así un horrible regreso de la esclavitud a un pueblo que había luchado mucho para ser libre. De hecho, es en este primer sentido que el zombi hizo su primera aparición en la cultura pop mundial. Las películas estadounidenses utilizaron al zombi como símbolo de la magia exótica en lo que a menudo eran representaciones racistas del Caribe o, simplemente, de "otras" religiones. En otros lugares, los zombis surgieron como el temor de que le robaran el trabajo a uno, ya fuera por el regreso de la esclavitud absoluta o como una metáfora de la forma confusa y explotadora en que se manifestaron las nuevas formas de capitalismo en sitios como Sudáfrica.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Pero es posible que la mayoría esté familiarizada con las hordas que George Romero popularizara en su película "La noche de los muertos vivientes". En ella, este director presenta un mundo al revés en que los muertos insepultos vuelven a la vida. Es de destacar que Romero nunca usa el término "zombi", sino que los llama "gules", una referencia a un espíritu antropófago árabe. Los zombis a finales del siglo XX se convirtieron en una nueva metáfora, al aparecer como manifestaciones del consumismo sin sentido y sin alma, temor por la lluvia radiactiva o la amenaza de una agitación social masiva. En el siglo XXI, los zombis se han asociado estrechamente al miedo a las enfermedades y al colapso de la sociedad. El locus del horror ha cambiado del miedo a perder el control de uno a la fantasía de sobrevivir después de que todo lo demás haya muerto al parecer. Aquí, los zombis son esa fuerza del todo destructiva... y que, posiblemente, puedas utilizar en tu beneficio.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Una mejora inviable antigua que inflige una pequeña cantidad de daño a las unidades hostiles que la crucen o estén adyacentes y ejerce una zona de control sobre ellas. Se desbloquea con la Ingeniería militar y se construye usando una carga de Constructor. No impide que las unidades pasen por esta casilla.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Una mejora inviable moderna que inflige una cantidad de daño moderada a las unidades hostiles que la crucen o estén adyacentes y ejerce una zona de control sobre ellas. Se desbloquea con Rayado del ánima y se construye usando una carga de Ingeniero militar. No impide que las unidades pasen por esta casilla.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Una mejora inviable antigua que inflige una cantidad de daño moderada y reduce el movimiento de las unidades hostiles que la crucen. Se desbloquea con la Construcción y se construye usando una carga de Constructor. No impide que las unidades pasen por esta casilla.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Una mejora inviable moderna que inflige una cantidad de daño importante y reduce el movimiento de las unidades hostiles que la crucen. Se desbloquea con Balística y se construye usando una carga de Ingeniero militar. No impide que las unidades pasen por esta casilla.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_RELIGIOUS_DESCRIPTION" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Tras completar este proyecto, tomas el control de los zombis que en ese momento se encuentren en el territorio de esta ciudad.  El control dura 15 turnos.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_SCIENCE_DESCRIPTION" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Tras completar este proyecto, tomas el control de los zombis que en ese momento se encuentren en el territorio de esta ciudad.  El control dura 30 turnos.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_DESCRIPTION" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Una unidad de cuerpo a cuerpo hostil que tiene una probabilidad de aparecer en un lugar del mapa donde haya muerto una unidad. Su Fuerza cuerpo a cuerpo aumenta con cada Zombi que se elimine en cualquier lugar del mundo. Si un Zombi destruye a otra unidad, al turno siguiente, aparecerá una nueva unidad de Zombi en esa casilla. Si un Zombi reduce la población de una ciudad, al turno siguiente, aparecerá una nueva unidad de Zombi al lado de la ciudad. Los Zombis atacan la unidad, ciudad o distrito defendible que se encuentre más cerca.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITCOMMAND_RELEASE_LEVY_DESCRIPTION" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Dejas de controlar a esta unidad.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITCOMMAND_SPY_SUMMON_ZOMBIES_NAME" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Brote zombi</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITCOMMAND_SPY_SUMMON_ZOMBIES_DESCRIPTION" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Tras completarse, tiene una probabilidad de generar un Zombi en cada casilla que esta ciudad explote.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_MESSAGE" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Brote zombi iniciado con éxito</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_ENEMY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_MESSAGE" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>El enemigo ha iniciado un brote zombi</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Inflige una pequeña cantidad de daño a las unidades hostiles que entren en esta casilla y agota el Movimiento de estas.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_TRAP" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Inflige una cantidad de daño moderada a las unidades hostiles que entren en esta casilla y agota el Movimiento de estas.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_BARRICADE" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Inflige una pequeña cantidad de daño a las unidades hostiles que entren en esta casilla y circundantes y ejerce una zona de control sobre ellas.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TOWERDEFENSE_ZOMBIE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_DESC" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>+{Property} a la Fuerza de la mutación</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_SUMMARY" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Tu agente {1_unitName}, de misión en {2_CityName}, ha conseguido infectar a la población y crear una horda zombi que ataque la ciudad.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_ENEMY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_SUMMARY" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Un espía enemigo en {1_CityName} ha conseguido infectar a la población y crear una horda zombi que ahora amenaza tu ciudad.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ALCAZAR_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ALCAZAR_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MAORI_PA_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MAORI_PA_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ROMAN_FORT_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ROMAN_FORT_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_FORT_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_FORT_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_VAMPIRE_CASTLE_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_VAMPIRE_CASTLE_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_GREAT_WALL_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_GREAT_WALL_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_BARRICADE}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_NAME" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Zombi</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>路障</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>加固路障</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>陷阱</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>現代化陷阱</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_RELIGIOUS_NAME" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>感化活死人</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_SCIENCE_NAME" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>黑暗訊號</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_CONTENT_TITLE" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>殭屍圍城</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_WELCOME_TITLE" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>歡迎</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_WELCOME_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>「殭屍圍城」遊戲模式將對你的文明帶來嚴重威脅：死人開始不安於室。殭屍可從戰爭煙硝中復生，並且當它們肆虐你或其他人的土地時，還會開始散播其致命詛咒。試著不要讓它們在你的城市中恣意流竄，至少要再撐一回合啊！</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_TITLE" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>殭屍</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>殭屍是會在荒野中遊蕩的近戰單位。它們無法攻掠奪改良設施；因為那並不是它們的目標。但他們會朝任何在外面遊蕩的單位前進，所以在離開城市時，記得要多加注意。它們同時還能攻打城市，將遭到摧毀的人口變成更多殭屍...</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_2" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>當有單位在地圖中陣亡時，它會有極小機率在數回合後以殭屍單位形式回歸。但是，若一個單位遭到殭屍殺死，該單位便會在下一回合成為殭屍崛起。而且，活死人的邪惡勢力將緩緩壯大，地圖世界上任何一個殭屍遭到擊殺後，剩餘的殭屍及新出現的殭屍便會更為強大。所以當你準備和活死人開戰時，最好先搞清楚對手的實力！</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_3" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>聖地和學院能在面對殭屍群時提供暫時的解方。使用聖地的「感化活死人」項目，或學院的「黑暗訊號」項目，都可短暫控制位於城市範圍的殭屍，意思是你能讓殭屍轉而攻擊你的敵人，只要確保自己在失去控制或者戰術性結束控制前保有安全距離就行了。另外，你的間諜可使用「屍毒爆發」行動對敵人散播致死詛咒。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_TITLE" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>防禦手段</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>在殭屍群起而攻時，你的土地並非毫無防禦手段。除了在聖地和學院的項目外，你的建造者可建造出路障和陷阱來幫助禦敵（無論敵人是死是活）。路障可對任何經過或相鄰的敵對單位造成少量傷害，而陷阱則可對任何直接經過的敵對單位造成大量傷害。之後的時代則能賦予玩家製造更強大路障或陷阱的能力。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_PARA_2" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>雖然以上這些都是對抗活死人的強大防禦手段，但對於比較「有生氣」的敵人也同樣適用，因為它們對任何類型的敵人都能造成傷害。只要你妥善做好戰術性佈置，或許就能撐過夜晚的考驗。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>殭屍的不可思議之處來自於其模糊特性。它們到底只是種會動的物體，還是屬於某種生物？對抗人類的防禦手段都建立在幾種機制上：像是疼痛、威嚇和疲憊等，但這些對行屍走肉來說毫無用處，鐵絲網對沒有感覺的東西來說形同廢物。另外，殭屍的武器有限：它們不會建造投石機，也不會射箭。所以當你在對抗活死人時，不能把它當作會思考的人，而要把它當成一個會移動的東西。這意思是，削尖的棍子不是為了要擊殺它們，而是為了要限制行動；具有可收回梯子的塔樓可成為避難處，防止無腦敵人攀繩而上；溝渠也能困住不會造橋的敵人。至少在它們滿出來之前你都能高枕無憂。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>這群行屍走肉不知道疲憊，這是它們的絕佳優勢之一，它們會像海浪一樣，前仆後繼地向前推擠防禦工事。最終，城牆的木頭和竹子將會斷裂，甚至連石牆都會塌毀。因此，諸如鋼筋混凝土和鋼鐵等現代建材便可派上用場了。就如同文藝復興時期的星形要塞，它的多角城牆設計能彈偏加農砲砲火而非吸收其威力，現代的防禦手段也著重在卸去這些行屍走肉的攻勢，不求一味地擋下它們。在活死人永不放棄地推擠下，彈性建材可彎折但不會斷裂。光滑表面讓骨頭手指無縫可抓，而水門可讓壕溝和護城河排空，克服過往舊版殭屍防禦手段無法擺平的堆屍問題。我們躲在這些防禦後方應該會很安全，應該會吧。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>雖然城牆是能將敵人隔絕在外的防禦手段，陷阱卻能消滅、減緩或令殭屍們動彈不得。另外，這些行走屍體雖然不屈不撓，卻不怎麼聰明。只要有肥美多汁的大腦，即便城塔僅有一人也能成為堪用的誘餌，而這招也適合用來除掉一個「毫無防備」的敵軍，你能將其引到殭屍附近讓它們代勞除掉敵人。但處理死人比處理人類敵軍麻煩多了，你沒辦法把它們趕走，甚至重傷它們也沒用，唯一的辦法就是摧毀它們。古代的陷阱包括火把、坑洞或是單純用佈滿射手的城塔。當然啦，等箭用完你就知道了…</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>隨著時光流逝，我們對活死人的威脅有了更多瞭解。早期陷阱需要使用到人類（無論是否自願）當作誘餌，但工程師已研發出化學或動物替代物。另外，中空彈或反人員子彈增加了肉體傷害和精準度。不是每個射手都能用百步穿楊，步槍和瞄準鏡能帶來更精確的「擊殺」，而佈有狙擊手的碉堡無論對抗人類或是殭屍一樣有用。精煉燃油和汽油彈能以前所未有的方式摧毀殭屍，這一點在對抗人類敵軍也一樣。除此之外，現代陷阱會猛攻殭屍的弱點：殭屍群會無止盡地繞圈，並且追著裝在機械軌道上的大腦跑，這種宛若賽狗場的方式，將比單純挖坑更有效率。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>殭屍已成為最受公認的恐怖老哏之一。但殘暴且蹣跚的屍體形象，以及造成全球大流行的不死病毒等背景，可說是近年來才興起的概念。在許多加勒比海傳統民間故事中，殭屍（zombi或jumbee）原本泛指為充滿惡意的靈體，這說法源自西非傳統。但在海地，殭屍便成了另一種東西，它象徵了奴隸制的恐怖。對當時法屬聖多明哥的非洲奴隸來說，生活幾乎讓人難以承受。死亡，至少可以回歸到傳統文化中所指的非洲天堂，它們在那裡起碼能重獲自由。但自殺者無法前往此地，因為你的不幸靈體將會永遠迴盪在加勒比海為僕為奴，就如殭屍一樣。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>在海地革命興起之際，殭屍融入到了當地民間故事中，成為了邪惡術士的僕人，或者在其他說法裡，會成為巫毒（voodoo）術士。無論是被施法或重新賦予了生命，殭屍仍舊要為主人勞役，因此對辛苦贏得自由的人來說，這就是奴隸制可怕的回歸。的確，這就是殭屍甫登上全球流行文化時的印象。美國電影過去都將殭屍當作一個異國魔法的代表，因為當時常常會將種族歧視的眼光加諸在加勒比海或「其他」的信仰上。在其他地方，殭屍形象出現的原因，大都源自於懼怕自己的勞動成果被他人搶走，無論是害怕派奴隸制直接回歸，或是在南非等地，殭屍成了某種新式資本主義混淆剝削的暗喻體驗。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>但大多數人應該都很熟悉喬治·羅梅羅電影《活死人之夜》中的殭屍群，羅梅洛在此描述了一個顛覆的世界，他讓未下葬的死人重新活了過來。值得注意的是，羅梅洛從未使用「殭屍（zombie）」一詞，他是稱它們為「食屍鬼（ghouls）」，其靈感是源自阿拉伯的食人靈體。殭屍在20世紀末有了新的暗喻，成為了毫無意義又空泛的消費主義形象代表、對核戰的恐懼、或是大型社會動亂的威脅。在21世紀時，殭屍變成恐懼疾病和社會崩潰的相似詞。這條恐懼的軌跡已大不相同，從害怕失去個體的控制，到末日倖存的幻想。到此，殭屍已成為最終極的毀滅力量，但話說回來，或許你也有機會操控這股力量。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>前期改良設施，公民無法在此工作，能對通過或相鄰之敵對單位造成少量傷害並發揮控制區影響。需要「軍事工程學」科技才能解鎖，建築時須耗用1點建造者使用次數。無法避免單位移動時穿過其所在空間。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>後期改良設施，公民無法在此工作，能對通過或相鄰之敵對單位造成中等傷害並發揮控制區影響。需要「膛線」科技才能解鎖，建築時須耗用1點軍事工程師使用次數。無法避免單位移動時穿過其所在空間。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>前期改良設施，公民無法在此工作，能對直接通過之敵對單位造成中等傷害並耗盡其移動力。需要「建設」科技才能解鎖，建築時須耗用1點建造者使用次數。無法避免單位移動時穿過其所在空間。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>後期改良設施，公民無法在此工作，能對直接通過之敵對單位造成大量傷害並耗盡其移動力。需要「彈道學」科技才能解鎖，建築時須耗用1點軍事工程師使用次數。無法避免單位移動時穿過其所在空間。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_RELIGIOUS_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>完成後，能控制目前位於此城市領土內的殭屍。可控制長達15回合。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_SCIENCE_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>完成後，能控制目前位於此城市領土內的殭屍。可控制長達30回合。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>一種敵對近戰單位，有一定機率會於地圖上有單位死亡之地點產生。全地圖遭到殲滅的殭屍越多，其近戰戰鬥力就越強。若殭屍殺死了其他單位，則此單位會在下一回合變為新的殭屍單位。若殭屍使某城市的人口減少，則該城市旁會立即生成新的殭屍單位。殭屍會以附近最近的單位、城市或可防禦的區域為目標。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITCOMMAND_RELEASE_LEVY_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>釋出此單位的控制權。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITCOMMAND_SPY_SUMMON_ZOMBIES_NAME" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>屍毒爆發</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITCOMMAND_SPY_SUMMON_ZOMBIES_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>完成後，有一定機率根據此城市中已改良單元格之數量來生成殭屍。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_MESSAGE" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>成功造成屍毒爆發</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_ENEMY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_MESSAGE" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>敵方已造成屍毒爆發</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>對走到此單元格之敵方單位造成少量傷害，並且耗盡其移動力。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_TRAP" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>對走到此單元格之敵方單位造成中等傷害，並且耗盡其移動力。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_BARRICADE" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>對走到此單元格以及鄰近單元格之敵方單位造成少量傷害並且發揮控制區影響。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TOWERDEFENSE_ZOMBIE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_DESC" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>+{Property} 突變戰鬥力</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_SUMMARY" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>你的探員{1_unitName}成功感染了{2_CityName}的人口，創造出會攻擊城市的殭屍群。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_ENEMY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_SUMMARY" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>在{1_CityName}的敵方間諜成功感染了你的人口，創造出威脅你城市的殭屍群。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ALCAZAR_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ALCAZAR_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MAORI_PA_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MAORI_PA_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ROMAN_FORT_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ROMAN_FORT_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_FORT_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_FORT_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_VAMPIRE_CASTLE_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_VAMPIRE_CASTLE_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_GREAT_WALL_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_GREAT_WALL_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_BARRICADE}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_NAME" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>殭屍</Text>
    </Replace>
  </LocalizedText>
</GameData>