<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<GameData>
  <LocalizedText>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_BARRICADE" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_BARRICADE]Deals minor damage to and exerts zone of control on hostile units walking onto this tile and those surrounding it.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_TRAP" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_TRAP]Deals moderate damage to and depletes the movement of hostile units walking onto this tile.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP]Deals minor damage to and depletes the movement of hostile units walking onto this tile.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ALCAZAR_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ALCAZAR_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE]{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ALCAZAR_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_DESC]An unworkable early Improvement that deals minor damage to, and exerts zone of control on, hostile units passing through or adjacent to it. Unlocked with Military Engineering and built using a Builder Charge. Does not prevent unit movement through this space.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_NAME]Barricade</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_DESC]An unworkable early Improvement that deals moderate damage to, and depletes the movement of, hostile units passing directly through it. Unlocked with Construction and built using a Builder Charge. Does not prevent unit movement through this space.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_NAME]Trap</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_FORT_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_IMPROVEMENT_FORT_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE]{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_FORT_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_GREAT_WALL_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_IMPROVEMENT_GREAT_WALL_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE]{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_GREAT_WALL_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_BARRICADE}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MAORI_PA_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MAORI_PA_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE]{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MAORI_PA_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_DESC]An unworkable later Improvement that deals moderate damage to, and exerts zone of control on, hostile units passing through or adjacent to it. Unlocked with Rifling and built using a Charge from a Military Engineer. Does not prevent unit movement through this space.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_NAME]Reinforced Barricade</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_DESC" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_DESC]An unworkable later Improvement that deals significant damage to, and depletes the movement of, hostile units passing directly through it. Unlocked with Ballistics and built using a Charge from a Military Engineer. Does not prevent unit movement through this space.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_NAME" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_NAME]Modernized Trap</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ROMAN_FORT_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ROMAN_FORT_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE]{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ROMAN_FORT_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_VAMPIRE_CASTLE_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_IMPROVEMENT_VAMPIRE_CASTLE_DESCRIPTION_ZOMBIE]{LOC_IMPROVEMENT_VAMPIRE_CASTLE_DESCRIPTION}[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{LOC_DESCRIPTION_ADDENDUM_WEAK_TRAP}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_ENEMY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_MESSAGE" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_ENEMY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_MESSAGE]Enemy Caused Zombie Outbreak</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_ENEMY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_SUMMARY" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_ENEMY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_SUMMARY]An enemy Spy in {1_CityName} succeeded in infecting your population, creating a Zombie horde that now threaten your city.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_MESSAGE" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_MESSAGE]Success Causing Zombie Outbreak</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_SUMMARY" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_NOTIFICATION_SPY_SUMMONED_ZOMBIES_SUMMARY]Your agent {1_unitName} in {2_CityName} succeeded in infecting the population, creating a Zombie horde to attack the city.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_CONTENT_TITLE" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_CONTENT_TITLE]Zombie Defense</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_PARA_1]Your lands are not without defenses against the horde. In addition to the Projects at Holy Sites or Campuses, your builders can create Barricades or Traps to help to fend off your enemies (living or dead). A Barricade deals a minor amount of damage to any hostile unit who passes through it or adjacent tiles, and a Trap deals a significant amount of damage to any hostile unit that passes directly through it. Later eras can grant the ability to create more powerful Barricades or Traps.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_PARA_2" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_PARA_2]While these can be powerful defenses against the living dead, they can also be useful against your more – vivacious – enemies, as they deal damage to any sort of enemy. Plan these strategically, and you might just last the night.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_TITLE" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_DEFENSES_TITLE]Defense</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_WELCOME_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_WELCOME_PARA_1]The Zombie Defense game mode introduces a dangerous threat to your Civilization: the dead that don’t stay dead. Zombies can rise from the ashes of war, and as they prey upon your and other’s lands, they spread their deadly curse onwards. Try to keep them from overwhelming your cities, at least for one more turn!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_WELCOME_TITLE" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_WELCOME_TITLE]Welcome</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_1]Zombies are melee units that wander the wastes. They cannot pillage your Improvements; they’re just not interested in that. But they will go immediately for any unit wandering about outside, so make sure that you keep an eye open when leaving your cities. They can also attack your cities, turning any destroyed Population into more zombies...</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_2" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_2]When a unit dies on the map, it carries a slight chance of returning as a Zombie unit some turns later. However, if a unit is destroyed by a Zombie, it will certainly rise again on the following turn. The undead menace steadily grows, though – for each Zombie killed anywhere in the world, remaining and new Zombies get stronger and stronger. Make sure you know what you’re getting into when you go to war with the dead!</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_3" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_PARA_3]Holy Sites and Campuses hold a temporary solution to the zombie horde. Using the Turn Undead project at a Holy Site, or the Dark Signal project at a Campus will allow you to briefly take control of Zombies within your city limits, meaning that you can turn the horde against your enemies. Just be sure to be safely out of reach when your control expires… or when you strategically end it. In addition, your Spies can spread the deadly curse to your enemies with the Zombie Outbreak action.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_TITLE" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ZOMBIE_SIEGE_CHAPTER_ZOMBIES_TITLE]Zombies</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TOWER_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1]The uncanniness of zombies comes from their ambiguity. Are they simply animate material, or are they living beings of a sort? Defenses against people rely upon a number of things that simply do not apply to walking corpses: pain, intimidation, exhaustion. Barbed wire means nothing to something that cannot feel. Additionally, zombie weaponry is limited: zombies do not build trebuchets; they do not fire arrows. So defenses against the dead treat the un-living not as a thinking enemy, but as moving matter – sharpened sticks to not seek to kill, but to immobilize, towers with retractable ladders provide refuge from enemies without brains to climb a rope, ditches contain enemies who cannot build a bridge. At least, until there’s too many of them.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_ANCIENT_TRAP_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1]While walls are a type of defense that seeks to keep enemies out, traps seek to eliminate, slow, or immobilize them. And while the walking dead are relentless, they are not clever. A single human in a tower, with his juicy human brain, can act as sufficient bait to bring the dead – or hostile humans looking to take out an “unguarded” enemy - in to close quarters where they can be dealt with. But dispensing of the dead involves much more than dealing with human enemies. They cannot be chased off, or even critically wounded; they must be destroyed. Ancient traps could involve burning pitch, hidden pits, or simply towers fill of archers. That is, until the arrows run out…</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TOWER_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1]The walking dead do not tire. This is their one great advantage – like a sea, they constantly push against defenses erected to stop them. Eventually, walls of wood and bamboo splinter, and even fieldstone walls crumble. Here, modern materials – reinforced concrete, steel – come in. Just as the Renaissance-era star fort, with its angled walls, was designed to deflect and not absorb the impact of cannon fire, modern defenses emphasize deflecting the walking dead, instead of simply stopping them. Flexible materials bend but do not break, as the dead push on them relentlessly. Smooth surfaces give no handhold to bony fingers, and sluice gates allow ditches and moats to be flushed out, preventing the corpse-pile ramps that could overcome older forms of zombie defense. We should be safe behind these. We should be.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_MODERN_TRAP_DEFENSE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1]As the years have gone on, we have learned more about the undead menace. Earlier traps involved using live humans (voluntary or otherwise) as bait, but engineers have developed chemical or animal substitutes. In addition, hollow-point or anti-personnel bullets provide increased damage to tissue and increased accuracy. Not every archer is William Tell, able to bullseye an apple with a crossbow bolt, and rifling and scopes mean more and more precise “kills”, and bunkers with snipers work just as well against the dead as they do against other enemies. Refined petroleum and napalm allow zombies – or human enemies - to be disintegrated in ways earlier materials could not. Additionally, modern traps play upon zombies’ weaknesses: a horde of undead endlessly marching in a circle, chasing a brain on a mechanical track as in a dog-racing circuit can be far more effective than a simple pit.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1]Zombies have become one of the most recognizable horror tropes. But the image of ravenous, shambling corpses, and especially the idea of a global pandemic of the undead is something that has only come about in recent years. In many Caribbean folkore traditions, a zombi or jumbee is a general category for a malevolent spirit, itself deriving from West African traditions. But in Haiti the zombie became something else – a stand-in for all the horrors of slavery. For enslaved Africans in the then-French colony of Saint-Domingue, life was nearly unbearable. Death, at least, promised a release and a return back to, so the tradition went, a paradise in Africa where at last they could be free. But suicide would close this door and cause the unfortunate spirit to remain forever in the Caribbean, forever enslaved – a zombie.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2]In the wake of the Haitian Revolution, the zombie entered into local folklore as the servant of a malevolent sorcerer, or, in some tellings, a priest of voudun (voodoo). The zombie, entranced or re-animated, continued to labor for their master, thus recalling a horrific return of slavery to a people that had fought hard to become and remain free. Indeed, it is in this first sense that the zombie made its first emergence into global pop culture. American films used the zombie as a symbol of exotic magic in what were often racist depictions of Caribbean or simply “other” religions. Elsewhere, zombies emerged as the fears of having one’s labor stolen away, whether by a return of outright slavery, or as a metaphor for the confusing and exploitative way that new forms of capitalism manifested in areas such as South Africa.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3]But most people might be familiar with the hordes made famous by George Romero in his film, “Night of the Living Dead.” Here, Romero presents a world turned upside down, as the unburied dead return to life. Notably, Romero never uses the term “zombie,” instead calling them” ghouls” – itself a reference to an Arabic cannibal spirit. Zombies in the late 20th century became a new metaphor, appearing as the manifestations of mindless, soulless consumerism; fears over nuclear fallout; or the threat of massive societal upheaval. In the 21st century, zombies became closely associated with a fear of disease and a collapse of society. The locus of horror had changed from a fear of losing control over oneself to a fantasy of surviving after everything else seemed to have died. Here, zombies are this utterly destructive force – destruction that you can, possibly, turn to your advantage.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_RELIGIOUS_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_RELIGIOUS_DESCRIPTION]Upon completion, gain control of the zombies currently in this city's territory.  Control lasts 15 turns.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_RELIGIOUS_NAME" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_RELIGIOUS_NAME]Turn Undead</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_SCIENCE_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_SCIENCE_DESCRIPTION]Upon completion, gain control of the zombies currently in this city's territory.  Control lasts 30 turns.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_SCIENCE_NAME" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PROJECT_CONVERT_ZOMBIES_SCIENCE_NAME]Dark Signal</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TOWERDEFENSE_ZOMBIE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_DESC" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_TOWERDEFENSE_ZOMBIE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_DESC]+{Property} Mutation Strength</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_DESCRIPTION]A hostile melee unit that has a chance to appear on the map at a location where a unit has died. Its Melee Strength increases with each Zombie that has been eliminated, globally. If a Zombie destroys another unit, a new Zombie unit spawns in that tile the next turn. If a Zombie reduces a city's population, a new Zombie unit will spawn immediately next to the city. Zombies target the closest nearby unit, city, or defensible district.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_NAME" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_UNIT_MODE_ZOMBIE_NAME]Zombie</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITCOMMAND_RELEASE_LEVY_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_UNITCOMMAND_RELEASE_LEVY_DESCRIPTION]Release control of this unit.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITCOMMAND_SPY_SUMMON_ZOMBIES_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_UNITCOMMAND_SPY_SUMMON_ZOMBIES_DESCRIPTION]Upon completion, has a chance to spawn a Zombie for each tile worked by this city.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNITCOMMAND_SPY_SUMMON_ZOMBIES_NAME" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_UNITCOMMAND_SPY_SUMMON_ZOMBIES_NAME]Zombie Outbreak</Text>
    </Replace>
  </LocalizedText>
</GameData>